<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Inward Spiral - Uncategorized</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/feeds/uncategorized.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/</id><updated>2013-01-08T10:32:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>Hitchhiker in the Noosphere</subtitle><entry><title>I know you better than you know yourself.</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2013/01/08/i-know-you-better/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-08T10:32:00+05:30</published><updated>2013-01-08T10:32:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2013-01-08:/2013/01/08/i-know-you-better/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reading an article about how Google+ is the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://venturebeat.com/2013/01/05/why-the-google-long-game-is-brilliant/"&gt;Why the Google+ long game is&amp;nbsp;brilliant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author is trying to make a point, and I get it. But when skimming, I just picked up the lines in bold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live in Gmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Voice is my phone …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reading an article about how Google+ is the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://venturebeat.com/2013/01/05/why-the-google-long-game-is-brilliant/"&gt;Why the Google+ long game is&amp;nbsp;brilliant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author is trying to make a point, and I get it. But when skimming, I just picked up the lines in bold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live in Gmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Voice is my phone number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Hangouts is my new calendar invite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live in Chrome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And then when I reached the end, I half-expected the following conclusion:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;... &lt;em&gt;and in case I don't see ya, good afternoon, good evening, and good night!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>The Hitchhiker's Guide to Git</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2012/10/12/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-git/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-12T10:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2012-10-12T10:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2012-10-12:/2012/10/12/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-git/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One needs the following in order face a git disaster and live to tell the story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humility, to read the fine manual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courage, to submit your code to the will of the force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common sense, to stop you from manually editing any file under ./.git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tactical smarts, because sometimes …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One needs the following in order face a git disaster and live to tell the story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humility, to read the fine manual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courage, to submit your code to the will of the force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common sense, to stop you from manually editing any file under ./.git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tactical smarts, because sometimes you need a sniper and sometimes you need a cavalry charge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisdom, to know when to give up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="blarg"></category><category term="don't panic"></category></entry><entry><title>You're probably doing it right when everyone starts complaining</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2011/10/17/youre-probably-doing-it-right-when-everyone-starts-complaining/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-17T15:35:00+05:30</published><updated>2011-10-17T15:35:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2011-10-17:/2011/10/17/youre-probably-doing-it-right-when-everyone-starts-complaining/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't remember who said that, but I do believe that's exactly what's happening with Ubuntu and the new Unity desktop. I have not tried it out yet, but given the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3118125"&gt;strong criticism&lt;/a&gt; that Unity is receiving, I believe it is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/805/trackback"&gt;all set for world domination&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't remember who said that, but I do believe that's exactly what's happening with Ubuntu and the new Unity desktop. I have not tried it out yet, but given the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3118125"&gt;strong criticism&lt;/a&gt; that Unity is receiving, I believe it is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/805/trackback"&gt;all set for world domination&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>getting back to the fun in computer programming</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/07/31/getting-back-to-the-fun-in-computer-programming/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-07-31T11:43:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-07-31T11:43:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-07-31:/2009/07/31/getting-back-to-the-fun-in-computer-programming/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First, a few quotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
A computational process is indeed much like a sorcerer's idea of a spirit. It cannot be seen or touched. It is not composed of matter at all. However, it is very real. It can perform intellectual work. It can answer questions. It can affect the world …&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First, a few quotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
A computational process is indeed much like a sorcerer's idea of a spirit. It cannot be seen or touched. It is not composed of matter at all. However, it is very real. It can perform intellectual work. It can answer questions. It can affect the world by disbursing money at a bank or by controlling a robot arm in a factory. The programs we use to conjure processes are like a sorcerer's spells. They are carefully composed from symbolic expressions in arcane and esoteric &lt;em&gt;programming languages&lt;/em&gt; that prescribe the tasks we want our processes to perform.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, learning to program is considerably less dangerous than learning sorcery, because the spirits we deal with are conveniently contained in a secure way. Real-world programming, however, requires care, expertise, and wisdom. A small bug in a computer-aided design program, for example, can lead to the catastrophic collapse of an airplane or a dam or the self-destruction of an industrial robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Lisp is not a mainstream language, why are we using it as the framework for our discussion of programming? Because the language possesses unique features that make it an excellent medium for studying important programming constructs and data structures and for relating them to the linguistic features that support them. The most significant of these features is the fact that Lisp descriptions of processes, called procedures, can themselves be represented and manipulated as Lisp data. The importance of this is that there are powerful program-design techniques that rely on the ability to blur the traditional distinction between ``passive'' data and ``active'' processes. As we shall discover, Lisp's flexibility in handling procedures as data makes it one of the most convenient languages in existence for exploring these techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Above and beyond these considerations, programming in Lisp is great fun.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us who already know what I am talking about, wish me luck! Those of us who don't, here's a four-letter word for you: SICP.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>horror at livejournal</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/07/22/horror-at-livejournal/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-07-22T09:55:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-07-22T09:55:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-07-22:/2009/07/22/horror-at-livejournal/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just noticed this weekend that I don't seem to have any control over ads that LiveJournal shows on my blog. Was browsing on a borrowed PC with no AdBlock, and was shocked to see the right side occupied by a huge flash video of a blonde teenager seemingly chatting on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just noticed this weekend that I don't seem to have any control over ads that LiveJournal shows on my blog. Was browsing on a borrowed PC with no AdBlock, and was shocked to see the right side occupied by a huge flash video of a blonde teenager seemingly chatting on a laptop and &amp;quot;pointing downwards&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I get out of this mess? Can I choose which ads show up on livejournal? Or should I jump ship already?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>No Mono!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/07/03/no-mono/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-07-03T09:31:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-07-03T09:31:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-07-03:/2009/07/03/no-mono/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone who uses the Gnome desktop is familiar with one of either Tomboy or F-Spot ... two tools that have become poster boys of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mono-project.com/"&gt;Mono project&lt;/a&gt;. Well, I decided to stop using them. Not only that, I decided to purge the root of evil, which is the Mono project …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone who uses the Gnome desktop is familiar with one of either Tomboy or F-Spot ... two tools that have become poster boys of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mono-project.com/"&gt;Mono project&lt;/a&gt;. Well, I decided to stop using them. Not only that, I decided to purge the root of evil, which is the Mono project itself from my Desktop. The philosophical and legal mind-bending around Mono is old news for those who are in touch with the times, but I had chosen to ignore all that till now, but not anymore. I just purged Mono and anything that depends on it from my desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What triggered this allergic reaction was a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=2009062823330395"&gt;post on Groklaw&lt;/a&gt; about a patch to the VFAT filesystem in the Linux kernel that circumvents Microsoft's patent on long file names in FAT. The patent is about storing both the long name and the short name of the file on disc. The patch beats that by storing only one of the two. How lame is that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a bunch of opinions about the whole issue, that started with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://groklaw.net/staticpages/index.php?page=archives&amp;amp;year=-1&amp;amp;use_s_page=TomTomTL"&gt;Microsoft suing TomTom&lt;/a&gt; over eight software patents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="first line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.softwarefreedom.org/news/2009/mar/30/settled-not-over-yet/"&gt;SFLC: Settled, But Not Over Yet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FAT filesystem patents on which Microsoft sued are now and have always been invalid patents in our professional opinion. SFLC remains committed to protecting the interests of our clients and the community. We will act forcefully to protect all users and developers of free software against further intimidation or interference from these patents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="first line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/12068_3812891_1/Bruce-Perens-Microsoft-and-TomTom-Settle-Justice-and-Linux-Lose.htm"&gt;Bruce Perens: Microsoft and TomTom Settle, Justice and Linux Lose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice lost because there's been no trial to overturn the FAT filesystem patents. As venture capitalist Larry Augustin wrote: &amp;quot;Those of us who have PhDs in computer disciplines and have studied operating systems and file systems, don't see anything particularly innovative in FAT or its extension to support longer file names, FAT32.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let's not forget Microsoft. All of that talk about interoperability with Linux coming from them? It was just talk, because they've shown that anyone who tries to interoperate with Microsoft technology even as simple as the FAT filesystem will eventially be sued, or pushed into licensing, for their efforts. The way they act, the Microsoft-internal definition of &amp;quot;interoperability&amp;quot; must be &amp;quot;making the whole world owe us.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, you should be wary of FAT, Office Open XML, .NET (including Mono), Silverlight, and of Microsoft's participation in standards committees that don't have a clear royalty-free committment, or, as is the case for Office Open XML, when the royalty-free committment is less than complete. These technologies leave the door open for submarine patents to sink your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="first line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brian-kahin/microsoft-roils-the-world_b_171985.html"&gt;Microsoft Roils the World with FAT Patents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft has abandoned its long history of not suing on software patents, in order to attack the Linux operating system. (Other patents at issue are specific to GPS systems.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By demonstrating its willingness to sue a small company, Microsoft can induce others to settle, while undermining confidence in the market for embedded Linux. By contrast, when IBM sought to impress the world with its patent portfolio, it at least picked on Amazon -- a company able to defend itself and with a reputation for asserting patents aggressively. (Remember the one-click ordering patent that Amazon used in its holiday-season attack on Barnes and Noble?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="mammon"></category></entry><entry><title>verbatim, etc. in beamer</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/07/02/verbatim-etc-in-beamer/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-07-02T16:32:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-07-02T16:32:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-07-02:/2009/07/02/verbatim-etc-in-beamer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been unsuccessful at creating a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;verbatim&lt;/tt&gt; environment in a beamer frame. The manual says that it is fully supported, and all you have to do is set the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;[fragile]&lt;/tt&gt; argument for that slide. So the following is supposed to work. (Note the weird indenting, since &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;verbatim&lt;/tt&gt; has to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been unsuccessful at creating a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;verbatim&lt;/tt&gt; environment in a beamer frame. The manual says that it is fully supported, and all you have to do is set the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;[fragile]&lt;/tt&gt; argument for that slide. So the following is supposed to work. (Note the weird indenting, since &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;verbatim&lt;/tt&gt; has to be at the beginning of the line.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
  begin{frame}[fragile]
    frametitle{Euclid says ``hello''}
    begin{verbatim}
blah...
and blah...
end{verbatim}
  end{frame}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I tried compiling it, and it doesn't. LaTeX exits with the following error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Runaway argument?
! File ended while scanning use of next.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took some time to get to the bottom of this. The problem is that a fragile frame &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; end at the start of a new line! I am an indentation-freak ... I indent LaTeX files even when Emacs doesn't. So I ended up with the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;end{frame}&lt;/tt&gt; indented by a couple of spaces. That's what choked LaTeX. So the above example works when changed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
  begin{frame}[fragile]
    frametitle{Euclid says ``hello''}
    begin{verbatim}
blah...
and blah...
end{verbatim}
end{frame}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posting this here for the record, with the hope that it will show up in the search results when some other poor sod is bugged by the same problem!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="beamer"></category><category term="latex"></category><category term="presentations"></category></entry><entry><title>completing the circle</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/05/13/completing-the-circle/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-05-13T13:02:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-05-13T13:02:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-05-13:/2009/05/13/completing-the-circle/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have always fancied myself as a small-time free software contributor, fixing a line of code here, filing a useful bug report there, and occasionally jumping into discussions. But finally I&amp;nbsp;got around to putting in a concrete contribution that is worth mentioning. The latest version of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://live.gnome.org/Dia"&gt;Dia&lt;/a&gt; is about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have always fancied myself as a small-time free software contributor, fixing a line of code here, filing a useful bug report there, and occasionally jumping into discussions. But finally I&amp;nbsp;got around to putting in a concrete contribution that is worth mentioning. The latest version of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://live.gnome.org/Dia"&gt;Dia&lt;/a&gt; is about to be &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/dia-list/2009-May/msg00001.html"&gt;released&lt;/a&gt;, and I have been responsible for scratching an itch that has been bothering people &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=60331"&gt;for years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in case you are an engineer that has to create lots of schematics, and you don't know what Dia is, it's high time you tried it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="free software"></category></entry><entry><title>my kind of notebook PC is finally here!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/05/03/my-kind-of-notebook-pc-is-finally-here/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-05-03T21:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-05-03T21:36:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-05-03:/2009/05/03/my-kind-of-notebook-pc-is-finally-here/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally decided that I do need a notebook now. The correct segment for me seems to be ultra-thin notebooks, rather than a netbook. And just in time, here comes the HP&amp;nbsp;DV2. The general &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.techtree.com/India/Reviews/HP_DV2_1003AX_Review/551-101428-616-1.html"&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://reviews.cnet.com/laptops/hp-pavilion-dv2/4505-3121_7-33483187.html"&gt;on&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pcworld.com/reviews/product/58935/review/pavilion_dv2.html"&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.notebookreview.com/default.asp?newsID=4963&amp;amp;review=hp+pavilion+dv2"&gt;inter-tubes&lt;/a&gt; suggests that it's a good buy. It fulfills the following things that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally decided that I do need a notebook now. The correct segment for me seems to be ultra-thin notebooks, rather than a netbook. And just in time, here comes the HP&amp;nbsp;DV2. The general &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.techtree.com/India/Reviews/HP_DV2_1003AX_Review/551-101428-616-1.html"&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://reviews.cnet.com/laptops/hp-pavilion-dv2/4505-3121_7-33483187.html"&gt;on&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pcworld.com/reviews/product/58935/review/pavilion_dv2.html"&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.notebookreview.com/default.asp?newsID=4963&amp;amp;review=hp+pavilion+dv2"&gt;inter-tubes&lt;/a&gt; suggests that it's a good buy. It fulfills the following things that I&amp;nbsp;am looking for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light (it's only 4 pounds ... 1.8kg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comfortable keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12&amp;quot; screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decently powerful, for a few things beyond email and surfing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth as well as dot-11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large hard-disc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Affordable&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few questions remain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it run Ubuntu? Also, can I &amp;quot;upgrade&amp;quot; the bundled Vista to XP, sitting in India?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This product is AMD's way to break into a whole new market segment between netbooks and notebooks. Will better things come along (I think it's not worth waiting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless I hear anything really bad about it soon, I think I'll just go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="notebook"></category></entry><entry><title>on becoming a father ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/04/21/on-becoming-a-father/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-04-21T15:13:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-04-21T15:13:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-04-21:/2009/04/21/on-becoming-a-father/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After I became a father, the one question that has been asked most frequently is, of course, &amp;quot;So, how does it feel to be a father?&amp;quot;. It's impossible to describe that feeling in words, but here are a few things so you get the hint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you have just become …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After I became a father, the one question that has been asked most frequently is, of course, &amp;quot;So, how does it feel to be a father?&amp;quot;. It's impossible to describe that feeling in words, but here are a few things so you get the hint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you have just become a father, it's okay to walk down the road with a completely silly smile slapped on your face. You can't control it any way, so why bother!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compared to the experience of becoming parents, the experience of being married is like holding a candle to the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The one thing that you will want to do is sit next to the baby and just keep looking at her. Go ahead and do that, it's amazing ... you'll never notice how time flies by.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And an important thing to remember:&amp;nbsp;Try not to fight with your spouse about who gets to hold the baby more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="phase three"></category></entry><entry><title>accord with Hrithik?</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2009/03/14/accord-with-hrithik/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-03-14T20:24:00+05:30</published><updated>2009-03-14T20:24:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2009-03-14:/2009/03/14/accord-with-hrithik/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seems that umbilical cord blood banking in India received some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mumbaimirror.com/index.aspx?Page=article&amp;amp;sectname=News%20-%20City&amp;amp;sectid=2&amp;amp;contentid=2008111420081114021230454d5632ca#ftr2"&gt;starry recognition&lt;/a&gt; recently. There's also a rather informative general &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://science.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=09/01/28/0018207"&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; about it on Slashdot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't made up my mind about it yet, but I am pretty sure it's all a waste of money for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It smells …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seems that umbilical cord blood banking in India received some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mumbaimirror.com/index.aspx?Page=article&amp;amp;sectname=News%20-%20City&amp;amp;sectid=2&amp;amp;contentid=2008111420081114021230454d5632ca#ftr2"&gt;starry recognition&lt;/a&gt; recently. There's also a rather informative general &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://science.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=09/01/28/0018207"&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; about it on Slashdot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't made up my mind about it yet, but I am pretty sure it's all a waste of money for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It smells like a scam ... just like ULIPs, endowments, child plans, etc:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Do it for the kids!&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;You need it. We know better.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nobody really knows whether and how long cord cells can remain viable in cryogenic storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent research indicates that it will soon be practical to reprogram somatic cells to do what you need ... basically researches have managed to use cells from skin, teeth, bone marrow in rather interesting regeneration procedures, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cnn.com/2008/HEALTH/11/19/windpipe.transplant/index.html"&gt;reconstructing a windpipe using stem cells from the bone marrow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cord cells have the same genetic defects as the child, so they can't be used to treat leukemia etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all this, it makes quite a lot of sense to donate those cord cells, either to a public bank, or to stem cell research, rather than spending money on storing them. In the long term, it seems the preserved cord cells will be mostly unnecessary. But I don't think either of these alternatives are very interesting in India yet!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="idle thoughts"></category><category term="phase three"></category></entry><entry><title>chasing mystery girls</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2008/12/24/chasing-mystery-girls/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-12-24T07:21:00+05:30</published><updated>2008-12-24T07:21:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2008-12-24:/2008/12/24/chasing-mystery-girls/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu is playing with a new idea for desktop notifications ... you can watch a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/253/trackback"&gt;video on Mark Shuttleworth's blog&lt;/a&gt;. They are supposed to be ephemeral, non-actionable pop-ups that &amp;quot;are gone like a mystery girl on the bus you didn’t get on&amp;quot; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw the video, and I say desktop notifications …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu is playing with a new idea for desktop notifications ... you can watch a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/253/trackback"&gt;video on Mark Shuttleworth's blog&lt;/a&gt;. They are supposed to be ephemeral, non-actionable pop-ups that &amp;quot;are gone like a mystery girl on the bus you didn’t get on&amp;quot; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw the video, and I say desktop notifications should not appear in the first place. I hope they create the option to turn them off before they start coding those ghastly distracting things! The only thing that I ever want popping up is an event that needs my attention, not want it. In that sense, they should be like the wife that you should not ignore, rather than the mystery girl you shouldn't be worried about anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always wondered what it is about the Linux desktop that is so great compared to Windows, and this is one of those features ... the desktop doesn't take your eyes off your work unless it's important! And now, the flagship Linux desktop wants to do just that!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="desktop"></category></entry><entry><title>it is done.</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2008/12/03/it-is-done/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-12-03T16:18:00+05:30</published><updated>2008-12-03T16:18:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2008-12-03:/2008/12/03/it-is-done/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=590"&gt;submitted my thesis&lt;/a&gt;. And people are glad that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=408"&gt;it is over&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=590"&gt;submitted my thesis&lt;/a&gt;. And people are glad that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=408"&gt;it is over&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="phd"></category></entry><entry><title>sitting on the desktop fence</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2008/06/28/sitting-on-the-desktop-fence/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-06-28T08:53:00+05:30</published><updated>2008-06-28T08:53:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2008-06-28:/2008/06/28/sitting-on-the-desktop-fence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A long long time ago, I first saw a true Desktop for Linux when KDE was first announced. But later came GNU's response in the form of GNOME, with its radical focus on desktop usability. Once I switched to GNOME, I never felt like going back to KDE inspite of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A long long time ago, I first saw a true Desktop for Linux when KDE was first announced. But later came GNU's response in the form of GNOME, with its radical focus on desktop usability. Once I switched to GNOME, I never felt like going back to KDE inspite of the warts. Things have come full circle now, with KDE taking some great steps towards usability. It seems now that I just might decide to switch when &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080627-first-look-kde-4-1-beta-2-shows-solid-improvements.html"&gt;KDE 4.1&lt;/a&gt; is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yeah, I know, believe and rejoice in the all-powerful command line, but using a desktop does not in any way take away its power. For some simple yet frequent things in life, the command line is simply not enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="desktop"></category><category term="kde"></category><category term="usability"></category></entry><entry><title>a small step in the academic process ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2008/05/27/a-small-step-in-the-academic-process/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-05-27T21:35:00+05:30</published><updated>2008-05-27T21:35:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2008-05-27:/2008/05/27/a-small-step-in-the-academic-process/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;... but a giant leap for the man involved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done with the pre-synopsis seminar today. After a little less than five years and a half, the PhD is in its final lap now. Four months to submit the thesis, and then I get to change the title before my name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;... but a giant leap for the man involved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done with the pre-synopsis seminar today. After a little less than five years and a half, the PhD is in its final lap now. Four months to submit the thesis, and then I get to change the title before my name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been emotional. :D&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="don't panic"></category><category term="phd"></category></entry><entry><title>on the use of pre- and post- increment iterators, and erasing elements from an STL map</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2008/03/06/on-the-use-of-pre-and-post-increment-iterators-and-erasing-elements-from-an-stl-map/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-03-06T12:28:00+05:30</published><updated>2008-03-06T12:28:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2008-03-06:/2008/03/06/on-the-use-of-pre-and-post-increment-iterators-and-erasing-elements-from-an-stl-map/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After spending a tense 2-3 hours trying to track down a segmentation fault, here's what I found. The explanation is subtle and obscure enough to be documented in every text book that ever claims to teach &amp;quot;proper&amp;quot; C/C++ programming practices! Maybe they already do that, and I didn't happen …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After spending a tense 2-3 hours trying to track down a segmentation fault, here's what I found. The explanation is subtle and obscure enough to be documented in every text book that ever claims to teach &amp;quot;proper&amp;quot; C/C++ programming practices! Maybe they already do that, and I didn't happen to read the right books. I do admit to learning most of my programming skills on the fly from existing good code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the following function calls:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;f(++i);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;f(i++);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common understanding of these calls translates them to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;i += 1; f(i);&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;f(i); i += 1;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that is not so! The post-increment operator used in the second call behaves in a more complicated way! What it really does, is to increment &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;i&lt;/tt&gt; &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the arguments to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;f()&lt;/tt&gt; are created, but &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the function is called. Thus the correct translation of the second function call is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;temp = i; i += 1; f(temp);&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn't look too different, but the subtlety involved would have saved me those couple of hours wasted in debugging. It happened when I was iterating over an STL map and wanted to delete some members, as follows, in pseudo-code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;for &lt;span class="pre"&gt;(map::iterator&lt;/span&gt; i = &lt;span class="pre"&gt;map.begin();&lt;/span&gt; i != &lt;span class="pre"&gt;map.end();&lt;/span&gt; ++i) { if (test(i)) erase(i); }&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;map.erase()&lt;/tt&gt; invalidates the iterator passed to it. So the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;++i&lt;/tt&gt; at the start of the next iteration no longer points to a valid iterator. The correct way to do this is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;for &lt;span class="pre"&gt;(map::iterator&lt;/span&gt; i = &lt;span class="pre"&gt;map.begin();&lt;/span&gt; i != &lt;span class="pre"&gt;map.end();)&lt;/span&gt; { if (test(i)) &lt;span class="pre"&gt;erase(i++);&lt;/span&gt; else ++i; }&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the use of the pre-increment operator in the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;else&lt;/tt&gt; part, since that saves the unnecesary creation of a temp variable. It is definitely a good practice to &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; use the pre-increment operator unless you are sure you need post-increment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story doesn't end here. What if &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;f()&lt;/tt&gt; expected a reference as its argument? It does receive a temporary copy and any changes the function makes will be lost. But the fact is that it &lt;em&gt;can't&lt;/em&gt; make those changes. It is important to note that the &amp;quot;translation&amp;quot; involving the variable &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;temp&lt;/tt&gt; is just a vague interpretation. That &lt;em&gt;pseudo-&lt;/em&gt;variable &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;temp&lt;/tt&gt; is actually an &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rvalue&lt;/tt&gt; and cannot be assigned this way ... it's just a way of showing something that the compiler does internally. The post-increment operator returns an &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rvalue&lt;/tt&gt; and that can only be passed as a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;const&lt;/tt&gt; reference to the function. The function being called has to be declared accordingly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These facts were learnt from an old &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://coding.derkeiler.com/Archive/C_CPP/comp.lang.cpp/2004-05/1726.html"&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; that I chanced upon while searching.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="cplusplus"></category><category term="iterators"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>emails trying to scam HDFC customers ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2008/02/06/emails-trying-to-scam-hdfc-customers/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-02-06T12:38:00+05:30</published><updated>2008-02-06T12:38:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2008-02-06:/2008/02/06/emails-trying-to-scam-hdfc-customers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you receive an email claiming to be from HDFC bank, be careful. I just received an email that asked me to click on a link. The image below is a screenshot of the email as it appears in thunderbird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that in the screenshot, the text &amp;quot;Netbanking Log-in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you receive an email claiming to be from HDFC bank, be careful. I just received an email that asked me to click on a link. The image below is a screenshot of the email as it appears in thunderbird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that in the screenshot, the text &amp;quot;Netbanking Log-in Review&amp;quot; does NOT link to the HDFC Bank website. The actual link can be seen at the bottom of the screenshot, next to the light bulb image. This link is visible when you move your mouse over the blue text, but unfortunately, the screenshot did not capture the mouse pointer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried reporting this to HDFC Bank, but the idiots who made that website have taken every possible effort to not reveal their customer service email address on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="screenshot of the fraudulent email" src="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/HDFC.jpg" style="width: 480px; height: 384px;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="email scam"></category></entry><entry><title>trite, feelgood, preachy, meretricious shit</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2008/01/04/trite-feelgood-preachy-meretricious-shit/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-01-04T10:59:00+05:30</published><updated>2008-01-04T10:59:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2008-01-04:/2008/01/04/trite-feelgood-preachy-meretricious-shit/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I thought I liked &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://xkcd.com/"&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt; for its wittiness. I think I still do. But here's something that managed to pull back some of the pretty dressing from XKCD :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://plover.net/~bonds/asdf.html"&gt;http://plover.net/~bonds/asdf.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the last word is in the tooltip! :))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I have no idea what &amp;quot;meretricious …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I thought I liked &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://xkcd.com/"&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt; for its wittiness. I think I still do. But here's something that managed to pull back some of the pretty dressing from XKCD :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://plover.net/~bonds/asdf.html"&gt;http://plover.net/~bonds/asdf.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the last word is in the tooltip! :))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I have no idea what &amp;quot;meretricious&amp;quot; means.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="comics"></category><category term="mlp"></category></entry><entry><title>seeking the light (part 3)</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/12/18/seeking-the-light-part-3/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-18T15:44:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-12-18T15:44:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-12-18:/2007/12/18/seeking-the-light-part-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got a reply from ICICI ... imagine the warm fuzzy feeling I experienced to know that they &amp;quot;regret the inconvenience&amp;quot; caused to me! The email I sent got submitted twice ... so waiting for a second dose of that warm fuzzy feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note to fellow ICICI sufferers: If you file a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got a reply from ICICI ... imagine the warm fuzzy feeling I experienced to know that they &amp;quot;regret the inconvenience&amp;quot; caused to me! The email I sent got submitted twice ... so waiting for a second dose of that warm fuzzy feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note to fellow ICICI sufferers: If you file a service request, and receive an email, don't forget to look beyond the disclaimer at the end ... it's usually the place where they put more important information about the service request.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="icici"></category><category term="marvin"></category></entry><entry><title>seeking the light (part 2)</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/12/12/seeking-the-light-part-2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-12T19:37:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-12-12T19:37:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-12-12:/2007/12/12/seeking-the-light-part-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a follow up to the previous post. Just one correction: the HDFC Bank website works quite well with Firefox ... it's the HDFC Securities website that sucks. Here's a reply to the reply from ICICI over my complaint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had filed a service request regarding the complaint tracking system, which …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a follow up to the previous post. Just one correction: the HDFC Bank website works quite well with Firefox ... it's the HDFC Securities website that sucks. Here's a reply to the reply from ICICI over my complaint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had filed a service request regarding the complaint tracking system, which does not seem to work with the Firefox web browser. I was contacted by a customer service officer, &amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;, who informed me that the ICICI Bank website works only with Firefox version 1.5, at a resolution of 800x600. At that time I had replied to him that this requirement is not acceptable given the current state of technology. But he insisted that this is all that the ICICI bank website supports, and he had promised me that he will forward this issue to the development team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not have a record of the actual service request number, but it is referred to with the identifier &amp;lt;snip&amp;gt; in the email that I received from the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a follow up to that, I would like to file a new service request further clarifying my original problem, as well as expressing my disappointment with the &amp;quot;disclaimer&amp;quot; on the ICICI Bank website regarding browser requirements. I have been forced to reboot into Windows solely for this purpose, because the complaint tracking system currently works only in Internet Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The issue I see with the complaint tracking system is a Javascript coding error, which is clearly visible in the Javascript debugging console in Firefox 2. I repeat, the problem is with the Javascript that is currently hosted on the ICICI Bank website, and not the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, the requirement that mentions Firefox 1.5 and a resolution 800x600 is not acceptable, and ICICI Bank should take prompt action to change it. Firefox 1.5 was released at the end of 2005. Right now, at the end of 2007, Firefox 3 is almost ready for release. Also, 800x600 is a decade-old requirement; no person who currently uses a computer works at a resolution less than 1024x768, and ICICI Bank's requirements are completely outdated in that context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problem (1) has nothing to do with problem (2), and yet another call from a non-technical staff instructing me to change the browser and the screen resolution that I use is not the relevant solution for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a comparison, here are the browser requirements from the HDFC Bank website, which incidently works flawlessly on Firefox, in both Windows and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;NetBanking at HDFC Bank works best with Internet Explorer 5.5 and above and Netscape 4.7 and above.&amp;quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the phrase &amp;quot;and above&amp;quot; included by HDFC Bank, where ICICI Bank mentions specific browser versions. Additionally, the HDFC Bank website does not mention any requirements for screen resolution, as opposed to the demand for a screen resolution of 800x600 at the ICICI Bank website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with my previous service request, I intend this as an open letter to ICICI, and a copy is posted on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="firefox"></category><category term="icici"></category><category term="standards"></category></entry><entry><title>seeking the light (part 1)</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/12/12/seeking-the-light-part-1/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-12T08:14:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-12-12T08:14:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-12-12:/2007/12/12/seeking-the-light-part-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been ranting about how the HDFC website sucks, for actually asking you to use IE and not working with any other web browser. But recently discovered that even the ICICI bank website suffers from this stupidity. Lodged a complaint with them, which I intend as an open letter …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been ranting about how the HDFC website sucks, for actually asking you to use IE and not working with any other web browser. But recently discovered that even the ICICI bank website suffers from this stupidity. Lodged a complaint with them, which I intend as an open letter. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a regular customer of ICICI Bank for a long time now. One thing that encourages me to continue working with ICICI is that the internet based services have always been well-maintained and functional. But I was disappointed with the new complaint tracking system introduced on the website. It does not work on any browser other than Internet Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An internet service should not force the user to select what kind of software they use on their computer. I am a Linux user, and run Firefox as the browser. Even when using Windows, I prefer Firefox when browsing. Besides being far more secure than Microsoft products, these software reflect my freedom to choose what software I use on my computer. The new complaint tracking system (that I am using right now to write this) takes this freedom away from me, and also forces me to use software that I cannot in any way rely on for security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this is a rather irresponsible move on the part of ICICI and urge you to move towards web standards compliance. If this rot spreads to the regular services on the ICICI internet banking site, I will be forced to close my account and move to a better bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend this as an open letter to ICICI bank rather than a single customer complaint. A copy of this has been put up on my blog as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="firefox"></category><category term="icici"></category><category term="standards"></category></entry><entry><title>power play</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/12/07/power-play/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-07T11:46:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-12-07T11:46:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-12-07:/2007/12/07/power-play/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We had some loose cash on our hands, and so decided to invest. Our regular investments happen in ELSS schemes, thanks to Section 80C. Besides that, we put some money every year in diversified equity funds and some hand-picked shares. This time, we decided to venture along a different route …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We had some loose cash on our hands, and so decided to invest. Our regular investments happen in ELSS schemes, thanks to Section 80C. Besides that, we put some money every year in diversified equity funds and some hand-picked shares. This time, we decided to venture along a different route -- sectoral funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that immediately came to mind was to put equal amounts in each sector. That sounded nice and easy, and looked like a good way to hedge against bad sectors. But then, isn't that what a diversified fund does, anyway? In fact a diversified fund is better at it than you putting money in all sectors by yourself. The latter implies that you have given a fixed weightage to every sector and you are unlikely to change it any time. But the management team for a diversified fund are likely to recalculate these weightages quite often, and churn their portfolio accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We checked the annualised returns on various sectors, and those on diversified funds. It did turn out to be as we expected -- rough calculations showed that putting 100 rupees in a diversified fund is much better than putting 20 rupees in five different sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, what are sectoral funds for? Its a mixed kind of risk for those who want just that right combination. We have diversified funds on one side, and hand-picked shares on the other. Sectoral funds fall in between -- we hand pick the general &amp;quot;kind&amp;quot; of companies when we choose a sector, and the fund is busy hand-picking the individual companies. This seemed just the right kind of arrangement to fill out a hole in our equity portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here is to place your bets on one or two sectors, and not all of them. The risk is that your bet may go wrong. The benefit is that if the bet goes the right way, you gain more than a diversified investment. And of course, the risk is less than hand-picking shares yourself. So for us, this kind of a risk just fit in with what we are already doing. But for others, this could mean a new kind of risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to place a bet on power and infrastructure. We believe its going to be good for the next few years. So we subscribed to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://myiris.com/mutual/announce/newSchemeDetail.php?scheme_fam=Sundaram+BNP+Paribas+Select+Thematic+Funds+Energy+Opportunities&amp;amp;fcode=SUNNEW_MF&amp;amp;icode=SUNBNPPARSE17_SC"&gt;NFO from Sundaram&lt;/a&gt; that ends on 11th December, for a three-year close ended fund in the power sector. We also invested some amount in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://myiris.com/mutual/scheme/index.php?icode=TATINFFUN-G_SC&amp;amp;fcode=TATA_MF&amp;amp;family=Tata+Infrastructure+Fund"&gt;Tata Infrastructure Fund&lt;/a&gt;, besides some routine investments in diversified funds. Now we wait and watch ... in the long term, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a key consideration to make when selecting funds, by the way ... never put too much money in the same fund house. You don't know when it could be hit by a scam, or by life in general. That means sometimes you have to choose the runner up instead of the best, but for me, the peace of mind is worth those lesser returns.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="investment"></category><category term="mutual funds"></category></entry><entry><title>ten minutes ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/11/20/ten-minutes/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-11-20T12:11:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-11-20T12:11:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-11-20:/2007/11/20/ten-minutes/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;... that's all the time it takes for your guide to brush off two days of work as amateurish crap, and put down a wonderful elegant solution to all your current woes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a day!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;... that's all the time it takes for your guide to brush off two days of work as amateurish crap, and put down a wonderful elegant solution to all your current woes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a day!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="don't panic"></category><category term="phd"></category></entry><entry><title>when investment meets insurance ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/11/16/when-investment-meets-insurance/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-11-16T14:27:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-11-16T14:27:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-11-16:/2007/11/16/when-investment-meets-insurance/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my regular ways of wasting time on the internet is reading about personal finance. Over the last couple of years, I have been totally convinced about the fallacy in &amp;quot;Jeevan ke saath bhi; jeevan ke baad bhi&amp;quot;. In general, any insurance scheme from any company, that promises you …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my regular ways of wasting time on the internet is reading about personal finance. Over the last couple of years, I have been totally convinced about the fallacy in &amp;quot;Jeevan ke saath bhi; jeevan ke baad bhi&amp;quot;. In general, any insurance scheme from any company, that promises you some kind of returns is simply not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have managed to force a number of my acquaintances to see the light, or at least agree with me in saying that there's something amiss about insurance policies the way they are advertised on TV. Here's a set of articles that gives the broad picture, though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=7/26/2005&amp;amp;story=5"&gt;Return of premium: What’s it worth?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This one is about how &amp;quot;money back&amp;quot; policies (from any company) are not as profitable as they seem.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=6/1/2005&amp;amp;story=1"&gt;Investments? Insurance? Or both?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;A similar analysis of endowment policies.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, these insurance policies disagree with my fundamental requirement that every rupee I save should continue to work for me, within reasonable parameters of risk v/s return. But on top of that, I suspect that these policies also actually lose money, once you bring inflation into the picture. Unfortunately I have yet to get enough insight to do an actual analysis of the effect of inflation, so it remains only a suspicion right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a bunch of articles on advise about how to approach insurance, whether or not one agrees with the articles quoted above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=1/30/2006&amp;amp;story=2"&gt;4 common life insurance mistakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=10/24/2007&amp;amp;story=2"&gt;Insurance: This time ask the right questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=6/21/2007&amp;amp;story=1"&gt;4 ULIP ‘sales pitches’ to beware of&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=11/21/2005&amp;amp;story=3"&gt;Mis-selling: ULIPs’ greatest bane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=2/16/2005&amp;amp;story=4"&gt;ULIPs? Read the fine print before investing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="insurance"></category><category term="investment"></category></entry><entry><title>gold may not be so attractive anymore ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/11/16/gold-may-not-be-so-attractive-anymore/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-11-16T14:03:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-11-16T14:03:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-11-16:/2007/11/16/gold-may-not-be-so-attractive-anymore/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happened to see this article today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=10/4/2007&amp;amp;story=1"&gt;Gold delivers… but not for you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gold has been a reasonably good investment for [the Indian investor] over the last few decades. And that’s not because gold has been a fundamentally strong asset. But because over most of the last three decades, the …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happened to see this article today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://personalfn.com/detail.asp?date=10/4/2007&amp;amp;story=1"&gt;Gold delivers… but not for you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gold has been a reasonably good investment for [the Indian investor] over the last few decades. And that’s not because gold has been a fundamentally strong asset. But because over most of the last three decades, the Indian Rupee actually lost value vis-à-vis the US Dollar. Yes, exactly the opposite of what you have witnessed this year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

The result was that even though the price of gold in US Dollar terms declined over most of this period, [the Indian investor] actually gained because the depreciation in the value of the Indian Rupee vis-à-vis the Dollar, more than made up for it!&lt;p&gt;If you believe that we are entering an era of a stronger Indian Rupee, then you should know that it is the fundamentals of gold which will drive the future price of gold; not any other factor as in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="gold"></category><category term="investment"></category><category term="rupee"></category></entry><entry><title>selecting a microwave oven</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/10/06/selecting-a-microwave-oven/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-10-06T20:13:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-10-06T20:13:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-10-06:/2007/10/06/selecting-a-microwave-oven/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Took a stroll in the kitchen-ware section of the friendly neighbourhood mall, looking at microwave ovens. We intend to buy one some time soon, but weren't sure what to look for, when selecting one. Here's a list of features to consider, that I collected through some searches on the net …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Took a stroll in the kitchen-ware section of the friendly neighbourhood mall, looking at microwave ovens. We intend to buy one some time soon, but weren't sure what to look for, when selecting one. Here's a list of features to consider, that I collected through some searches on the net. I ask the experienced among you ... which of these are relevant? Which are the must-haves, and the dont-cares?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user interface --- the front panel --- is there anything really convenient or really inconvenient to look out for, considering common daily usage, in the buttons, displays and settings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interior --- most are stainless steel, while others are some kind of polymer on metal or something. Which one lasts? And is also easy to clean?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Same for the door --- some have plastic doors, while others have metal doors. I don't suppose anyone uses glass for the transparent area, but if there is one with glass, will definitely consider that a plus point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The net recommends checking for grease filters that are easy to clean. Is that a big deal?
Delayed start timer --- almost all ovens seem to have that, these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep-warm modes after cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turntable, easily removable to facilitate cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safety interlocks on the door&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variable power setting (same as temperature?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensors to detect food done (I find this indistinguishable from magic, is technology sufficiently advanced to actually deliver this kind of functionality?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weight sensor to decide settings (kinda made sense to me when I saw one which had this)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave/Grill/Convection --- we decided we don't expect to be baking any cakes. But the grill seems like a &amp;quot;just-in-case&amp;quot; item that one might prove handy some time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, manufacturers --- which ones to totally avoid, and which ones to consider important enough to compromise on a feature above? Bajaj seems to be the only one that gives a one-year replacement guarantee. I liked the look of Onida ovens, but the flat interface of Panasonic ones seemed more convenient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="advice"></category></entry><entry><title>general purpose digital camera</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/09/28/general-purpose-digital-camera/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-09-28T14:46:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-09-28T14:46:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-09-28:/2007/09/28/general-purpose-digital-camera/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Was looking for a digital camera on behalf of a relative who just joined college, and I came up with this combination:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Canon-PowerShot-Digital-Camera-Optical/dp/B000HARTYI"&gt;Canon PowerShot A640 10MP Digital Camera with 4x Optical Zoom&lt;/a&gt; for $260&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two 2GB SD Memory cards ... one from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Kingston-2GB-Secure-Digital-SD/dp/B000EOMXM0"&gt;Kingston&lt;/a&gt; for $20 and one from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-Memory-SDSDB-2048-A10-Retail-Package/dp/B0009RGLSE"&gt;Sandisk&lt;/a&gt; for $16 …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Was looking for a digital camera on behalf of a relative who just joined college, and I came up with this combination:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Canon-PowerShot-Digital-Camera-Optical/dp/B000HARTYI"&gt;Canon PowerShot A640 10MP Digital Camera with 4x Optical Zoom&lt;/a&gt; for $260&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two 2GB SD Memory cards ... one from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Kingston-2GB-Secure-Digital-SD/dp/B000EOMXM0"&gt;Kingston&lt;/a&gt; for $20 and one from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-Memory-SDSDB-2048-A10-Retail-Package/dp/B0009RGLSE"&gt;Sandisk&lt;/a&gt; for $16.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Sandisk-MicroMate-Reader-memory-cards/dp/B000HDQ2G6"&gt;Sandisk MicroMate Reader&lt;/a&gt; for $10, just to put the memory cards to good use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mahaenergy.com/store/viewItem.asp?idProduct=339"&gt;Maha Powerex C401FS&lt;/a&gt; NiMH charger, with 8 2700mAh batteries, univeral adapter with European plug and a car adapter, all for $75.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera had to be a Canon, because a flip-out-and-twist LCD is a must. I selected the A640 (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_a640.asp"&gt;DPReview&lt;/a&gt;) because it gives the best bang for the buck for a casual user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_s5is.asp"&gt;S5 IS&lt;/a&gt; or its older sibling, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_s3is.asp"&gt;S3 IS&lt;/a&gt; are too big and need careful handling. You can't just casually throw one of these into your shoulder bag as you head for the beach on your college picnic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the A640, the current head of the line, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_a650is.asp"&gt;A650 IS&lt;/a&gt; has image stabilisation, more effective pixels and the newer Digic III processor with features for face recognition and stuff. But I didn't consider any of those worth the higher price. It also does not have manual controls for exposure (aperture priority and shutter priority). That last one is a personal preference, and I consider it worth the weightage when selecting a camera, for that rarely made, but stunning, long exposure photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another line, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_a720is.asp"&gt;A720 IS&lt;/a&gt;. It has one single missing feature that immediately eliminates it in my list ... the LCD is fixed, can't flip it out and twist it in whatever direction. It has one very big advantage though ... it uses only two batteries, and hence saves on overall weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the memory cards, decided to buy one of each brand simply because there didn't seem to be much difference between the two. The wife suggested hedging my bet on the brands instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maha Powerex C401FS, is the only known NiMH charger that is recommended by almost every photography site out there. It is supposed to be very gentle on the battery, and has four channels to charge each battery separately. Maha Powerex has a history of good products, and their 2300mAh batteries figured second in the only known thorough &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imaging-resource.com/ACCS/BATTS/BATTS.HTM"&gt;test of NiMH batteries&lt;/a&gt;, losing by just 2% behind the leader, Energizer. Had to order the package from the Maha website itself, since Amazon doesn't have that particular version ... universal adapter, European plug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The order hasn't been placed yet, but messages have been sent, and the said objects of desire will arrive Real Soon Now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>three men and a tube-light</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/08/02/three-men-and-a-tube-light/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-08-02T18:02:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-08-02T18:02:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-08-02:/2007/08/02/three-men-and-a-tube-light/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's stuff that could inspire a PhD comic! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Location: S24, the place where two old-timers from CSE can be found at random times of the day ... me and yogi, basically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time: about five minutes ago, late evening with the natural light going down to unacceptable levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In walks another …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's stuff that could inspire a PhD comic! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Location: S24, the place where two old-timers from CSE can be found at random times of the day ... me and yogi, basically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time: about five minutes ago, late evening with the natural light going down to unacceptable levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In walks another RS, , and is about to say &amp;quot;Hi!&amp;quot;. Instead I grab the opportunity and pre-empt him with a quick &amp;quot;Can you switch on the light please!&amp;quot; He is dazed, but I am dazed even further when Yogi (aka &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ppatil.wordpress.com/"&gt;Preetam Patil&lt;/a&gt;) says &amp;quot;Yeah, I have been hoping Sam will get up to turn it on!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category></entry><entry><title>across the lake</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/06/29/across-the-lake/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-06-29T09:41:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-06-29T09:41:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-06-29:/2007/06/29/across-the-lake/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Caught a bus towards home yesterday evening, and actually got a seat right away. Managed to view the Powai lake and campus from all sides, on my way towards Aarey colony. In the cloudy atmosphere shrouded further by the drizzling rain, &amp;quot;the Titanic&amp;quot; looked rather forelorn. I found myself traveling …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Caught a bus towards home yesterday evening, and actually got a seat right away. Managed to view the Powai lake and campus from all sides, on my way towards Aarey colony. In the cloudy atmosphere shrouded further by the drizzling rain, &amp;quot;the Titanic&amp;quot; looked rather forelorn. I found myself traveling from main gate to H12, and along the way passing gulmohar, the hospital, KReSIT, CC (which is almost rubble now), coffee shack, convo, MB, staff-C, SAC grounds, H11, H8 ... mostly places that I have not seen in quite a few months now, being in that limbo where I am a student yet, but not a resident anymore. Those few nanoseconds of FTL travel were filled with the ghosts of experiences long savoured, incidents long forgotten, people who have been real &amp;quot;teachers&amp;quot; to me, regardless of whether they were in the teaching profession or not ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found myself looking back at myself in the bus from the top of H12. But I didn't feel sad ... a smile crept over the face, and I felt strangely happy. &amp;quot;Home&amp;quot; is barely enough to describe what went through my mind. I wonder when I actually leave campus for good, will my last goodbye feel this way? I think I'll have to make do with the memory of yesterday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category></entry><entry><title>furniture to go ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/05/08/furniture-to-go/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-05-08T10:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-05-08T10:34:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-05-08:/2007/05/08/furniture-to-go/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had posted earlier about my fascination with some old furniture I checked out in Oshiwara. But better advice prevailed and all plans to buy that have been ditched. For a couple of reasons --- serious restrictions when considering interiors for the house that we will eventually buy, and the damn …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had posted earlier about my fascination with some old furniture I checked out in Oshiwara. But better advice prevailed and all plans to buy that have been ditched. For a couple of reasons --- serious restrictions when considering interiors for the house that we will eventually buy, and the damn things are two heavy to shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordered a cane sofa-set instead, along with a computer desk that can be dismantled, and two metal storewels, but not from Godrej, at half the Godrej price. Basically things that can be shifted when we move to yet another rented house later, and can be disposed off with very little repentance, once we have our own house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forecasts say that we will have to shift residence a maximum of two more times before we settle in a house of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="makaan"></category></entry><entry><title>moved!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/05/02/moved/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-05-02T14:22:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-05-02T14:22:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-05-02:/2007/05/02/moved/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shifted this weekend from a rented flat in Powai to one in Dindoshi ... quite close to Dindoshi Depot. It means a hefty increase in my commute time, going from basically nil to 40-plus minutes! But this will be good for Meenal, who's work is shifting to the new IFlex building …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shifted this weekend from a rented flat in Powai to one in Dindoshi ... quite close to Dindoshi Depot. It means a hefty increase in my commute time, going from basically nil to 40-plus minutes! But this will be good for Meenal, who's work is shifting to the new IFlex building near Movie Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently living out of boxes since we have no furniture of our own, and the flat has none. Made one visit to the old furniture shops in Oshiwara ... excellent stuff! Plan to start by buying a refurbished entirely-teak closet for clothes. We were also eyeing a counter with drawers and cupboards underneath, that would be just right for the TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More updates as things happen!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="makaan"></category></entry><entry><title>the end of an era</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/03/09/the-end-of-an-era/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-03-09T21:12:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-03-09T21:12:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-03-09:/2007/03/09/the-end-of-an-era/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went out to YP for lunch as usual, and the first thing I noticed was the colour yellow. A very specific kind of yellow. The one that Arthur Dent saw reflected in his shaving mirror that fateful day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yellow resolved itself into the shape of a bulldozer. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went out to YP for lunch as usual, and the first thing I noticed was the colour yellow. A very specific kind of yellow. The one that Arthur Dent saw reflected in his shaving mirror that fateful day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yellow resolved itself into the shape of a bulldozer. I crossed the road, and we stood face to face, both unaware of the ramifications that its presence implied, on the social future of the generations of IITians to come. Only after finishing my meal and leaving Harish did I see that something was amiss. The structures on either side of Harish were roofless. Further down the road, the smaller shops were almost entirely gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has reached Powai. The grand celebration of life in Mumbai called &amp;quot;road widening&amp;quot;. An unconfirmed rumour (heh!) has it that Lakshmi, SP and Harish are teaming up to manage a new eating joint in the mall built opposite Pizza Hut at the entrance to HN. Only one haunt will remain --- RK. RK was, and RK will be. Because RK is. Everything else is just floatsam and jetsam.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category><category term="sp"></category></entry><entry><title>so, how are you today?</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/03/06/so-how-are-you-today/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-03-06T12:16:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-03-06T12:16:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-03-06:/2007/03/06/so-how-are-you-today/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;That one is a real poser, you know. You are stumped and speechless, but you have to answer. Immediately. Without actually asking the other guy to (insert suitable colourful scene). But then I came across the Answer for this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Whenever you set out to do something, something else must …&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That one is a real poser, you know. You are stumped and speechless, but you have to answer. Immediately. Without actually asking the other guy to (insert suitable colourful scene). But then I came across the Answer for this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Whenever you set out to do something, something else must be done first.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is a bitch.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="blarg"></category><category term="marvin"></category></entry><entry><title>Friday night ramblings at SP ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/02/11/friday-night-ramblings-at-sp/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-02-11T09:38:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-02-11T09:38:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-02-11:/2007/02/11/friday-night-ramblings-at-sp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How to track progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS1: Boss, this is what I want to do.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS2: Boss, what have you done so far?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS3: Boss, finally managed to do this much.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS4: Boss, ab tak itna to kar diya, ab please de do na!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How to track progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS1: Boss, this is what I want to do.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS2: Boss, what have you done so far?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS3: Boss, finally managed to do this much.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;APS4: Boss, ab tak itna to kar diya, ab please de do na!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category><category term="farts"></category><category term="sp"></category></entry><entry><title>in the news</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/01/30/in-the-news/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-30T09:56:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-01-30T09:56:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-01-30:/2007/01/30/in-the-news/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The publication at VLSI07 seems to have attracted media attention. EE Times is running an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eetimes.com/showArticle.jhtml?articleID=196902462"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about it! They mailed saying they wrote about our work in their online edition, and now want to do a print version too! The article sure makes our work seem much larger than life …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The publication at VLSI07 seems to have attracted media attention. EE Times is running an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eetimes.com/showArticle.jhtml?articleID=196902462"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about it! They mailed saying they wrote about our work in their online edition, and now want to do a print version too! The article sure makes our work seem much larger than life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be good if we end up with a startup based on our work ... seems like a good idea too, what with all the VLSI design boom visible in our country.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="publication"></category></entry><entry><title>moving to a new lab!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/01/30/moving-to-a-new-lab/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-30T09:53:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-01-30T09:53:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-01-30:/2007/01/30/moving-to-a-new-lab/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The funding I received from the institute as a research scholar ended this month. So moving to the VLSI Lab, from my current office. Will get paid by the &amp;quot;VLSI Consortium&amp;quot; here for working as a sysad. Good to be root again!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The funding I received from the institute as a research scholar ended this month. So moving to the VLSI Lab, from my current office. Will get paid by the &amp;quot;VLSI Consortium&amp;quot; here for working as a sysad. Good to be root again!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>general updates</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/01/16/general-updates/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-16T15:51:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-01-16T15:51:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-01-16:/2007/01/16/general-updates/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Done with the paper presentation, comfortably settled back into the standard low-power &amp;quot;grad&amp;quot; operation mode. This second trip to Bangalore reinforced my infatuation with the city. Good to know that given the current situation of the VLSI Design industry, I am likely to spend a considerable amount of time living …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Done with the paper presentation, comfortably settled back into the standard low-power &amp;quot;grad&amp;quot; operation mode. This second trip to Bangalore reinforced my infatuation with the city. Good to know that given the current situation of the VLSI Design industry, I am likely to spend a considerable amount of time living in Bangalore after graduating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently working towards the APS, but looking forward to the weekend trip to Mahabaleshwar towards the end of the month, along with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://chetanv.livejournal.com/"&gt;chetanv&lt;/a&gt; and our respective SOs. That, followed by Roger Waters' &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/2007-tour-zone/february-18th-mmrda-bkc-grounds-mumbai-india.html"&gt;trip&lt;/a&gt; to Mumbai next month.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="mark"></category></entry><entry><title>Happy New Year ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2007/01/04/happy-new-year/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-04T10:04:00+05:30</published><updated>2007-01-04T10:04:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2007-01-04:/2007/01/04/happy-new-year/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The year has hardly begun, and it's already fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My first stint on the roads in a car, without an instructor. Drove around 25-30km from Dombivali to Titwala. Exhilarating, to say the least ... couldn't get over the excitement for a couple of days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's now cold enough to use the …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The year has hardly begun, and it's already fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My first stint on the roads in a car, without an instructor. Drove around 25-30km from Dombivali to Titwala. Exhilarating, to say the least ... couldn't get over the excitement for a couple of days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's now cold enough to use the ultra-soft, ultra-light rajai that we got from Simla. Heaven!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new semester begins ... I hit campus at 9:30, and the place is abuzz with students hurrying to their lectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My first &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/#publications"&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is likely to be my last Annual Progress Seminar in late January&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A conclusion in June to life as a grad student&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="driving"></category><category term="mark"></category><category term="new year"></category><category term="publication"></category></entry><entry><title>Universal! Basss.</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/12/28/universal-basss/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-12-28T15:55:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-12-28T15:55:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-12-28:/2006/12/28/universal-basss/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There was a time, when people bought Nokia phones because other people had Nokia phones. That way there was nothing to worry about if you forgot your charger ... there were always other chargers around. But now I have a Motorola, and I am as free as can be. It charges …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There was a time, when people bought Nokia phones because other people had Nokia phones. That way there was nothing to worry about if you forgot your charger ... there were always other chargers around. But now I have a Motorola, and I am as free as can be. It charges via USB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a relief it is, to know that the cable I carry around in my bag with my camera, will also let me charge my cellphone! Way to go, Moto! May the standards be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="motorola"></category><category term="standards"></category><category term="usb"></category></entry><entry><title>try again</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/12/26/try-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-12-26T10:47:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-12-26T10:47:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-12-26:/2006/12/26/try-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In case people had forgotten about me, I am still around. And currently approaching yet another phase of &amp;quot;will keep the blog updated&amp;quot;. So watch this space. &amp;quot;Main wapas aaoonga&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In case people had forgotten about me, I am still around. And currently approaching yet another phase of &amp;quot;will keep the blog updated&amp;quot;. So watch this space. &amp;quot;Main wapas aaoonga&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Gondor has arrived!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/08/23/gondor-has-arrived/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-08-23T14:41:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-08-23T14:41:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-08-23:/2006/08/23/gondor-has-arrived/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Found a small file called Isildur.pdf on the LAN ... and opened it out of curiosity! It seems to be just what the doctor ordered! Had been missing Fantasy for some time now ... this is the story of Isildur, that was never published because &amp;quot;Professor Tolkien&amp;quot;, according to the author …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Found a small file called Isildur.pdf on the LAN ... and opened it out of curiosity! It seems to be just what the doctor ordered! Had been missing Fantasy for some time now ... this is the story of Isildur, that was never published because &amp;quot;Professor Tolkien&amp;quot;, according to the author, did not permit spin-offs on his work.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was a man of contradictions and paradoxes: a valiant and merciless warrior but also a loving husband and father; esteeming virtue and honor above all things but intolerant of the weaknesses of others; of noble lineage and demeanor but also comfortable with his subjects and beloved by them. Even the great error that doomed him and marred the age that followed was not due to weakness on his part. It was his very nobility and virtue, his confidence in his ability to control Sauron's Ring that brought about his downfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His contemporaries heaped all praise and honor on him as a paragon of royal virtue, but his heirs had reason enough to curse his name. What sort of man was Isildur, the only Man to wear Sauron's One Ring? We decided to concentrate our research on this remarkable figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;From the Preface to:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;ISILDUR&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;by Brian K. Crawford&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;with Gary D. Crawford&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="reading"></category></entry><entry><title>define "huge"</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/08/10/define-huge/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-08-10T11:57:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-08-10T11:57:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-08-10:/2006/08/10/define-huge/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I usually ignore the articles in the Science section on slashdot after a quick look at the summary. But &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://science.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/08/07/1222245"&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; generated some pretty informative comments. Do read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://science.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=193313&amp;amp;cid=15859776"&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observable universe and the universe sound like the same thing but are not. Most of the universe is outside …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I usually ignore the articles in the Science section on slashdot after a quick look at the summary. But &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://science.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/08/07/1222245"&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; generated some pretty informative comments. Do read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://science.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=193313&amp;amp;cid=15859776"&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observable universe and the universe sound like the same thing but are not. Most of the universe is outside the observable part- outside the shell. If a galaxy is outside the shell, we'll never see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, the new improved frequency of slashback is pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="mlp"></category><category term="sci-tech"></category></entry><entry><title>deep thought</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/07/28/deep-thought/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-07-28T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-07-28T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-07-28:/2006/07/28/deep-thought/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Currently reading a wonderful article by Marvin Minsky - &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rci.rutgers.edu/~cfs/472_html/Intro/MinskyArticle/MM1.html"&gt;Why people think computers can't&lt;/a&gt;. Got caught up in one point that he puts forth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to think of learning as something that just happens to us, like a sponge getting soaked. But learning really is a growing mass of skills …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Currently reading a wonderful article by Marvin Minsky - &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rci.rutgers.edu/~cfs/472_html/Intro/MinskyArticle/MM1.html"&gt;Why people think computers can't&lt;/a&gt;. Got caught up in one point that he puts forth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to think of learning as something that just happens to us, like a sponge getting soaked. But learning really is a growing mass of skills: we start with some but have to learn the rest. Most people never get deeply concerned with acquiring increasingly more advanced learning skills. Why not'' Because they don't pay off right away! When a child tries to spoon sand into a pail, the child is mostly concerned with filling pails and things like that. Suppose, though, by some accident, a child got interested in how that pail-filling activity itself improved over time, and how the mind's inner dispositions affected that improvement. If only once a child became involved (even unconsciously) in how to learn better, then that could lead to exponential learning growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each better way to learn to learn would lead to better ways to build more skills ­ until that little difference had magnified itself into an awesome, qualitative change. In this view, first-rank &amp;quot;creativity&amp;quot; could be just the consequence of childhood accidents in which a person's learning gets to be a little more &amp;quot;self-applied&amp;quot; than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty insightful concept - learning to learn. But what made me sit up and &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to talk about it to someone was this footnote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Notice that there's no way a parent could notice ­ and then reward ­ a young child's reflective concern with learning. If anything, the kid would seem to be doing less rather than more ­ and might be urged to &amp;quot;snap out of it &amp;quot;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could this be what happens to most people? Being distracted by overbearing parents when they are just about to hit the zone? Does anyone remember something like this happening to them? Is this what makes a geek out of a child ... entering that phase of learning to learn, ever so slightly, not really reaching genius level?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="idle thoughts"></category><category term="reading"></category></entry><entry><title>TrustFlow results for sameerds</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/07/24/trustflow-results-for-sameerds/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-07-24T10:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-07-24T10:48:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-07-24:/2006/07/24/trustflow-results-for-sameerds/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first meme that begged me to post it on my blog with helpful &amp;quot;no cut-and-paste needed, and you can preview and edit it before posting&amp;quot;. So here it is! I tried out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://trustflow.lshift.net/?src=sameerds"&gt;TrustFlow II for LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt;. The following people not on the friends list for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sameerds.livejournal.com/"&gt;sameerds&lt;/a&gt; are close by …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first meme that begged me to post it on my blog with helpful &amp;quot;no cut-and-paste needed, and you can preview and edit it before posting&amp;quot;. So here it is! I tried out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://trustflow.lshift.net/?src=sameerds"&gt;TrustFlow II for LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt;. The following people not on the friends list for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sameerds.livejournal.com/"&gt;sameerds&lt;/a&gt; are close by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arundhatikane.livejournal.com/"&gt;arundhatikane&lt;/a&gt; (0 - 50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cyntalist.livejournal.com/"&gt;cyntalist&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://appughar.livejournal.com/"&gt;appughar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mighty_stylus.livejournal.com/"&gt;mighty_stylus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arnabdotorg.livejournal.com/"&gt;arnabdotorg&lt;/a&gt; (50 - 100)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://objectnut.livejournal.com/"&gt;objectnut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://premshree.livejournal.com/"&gt;premshree&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://apoorvs.livejournal.com/"&gt;apoorvs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swatisani.livejournal.com/"&gt;swatisani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vrigo.livejournal.com/"&gt;vrigo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dhempe.livejournal.com/"&gt;dhempe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vaibhav.livejournal.com/"&gt;vaibhav&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jnagal.livejournal.com/"&gt;jnagal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pooja.livejournal.com/"&gt;pooja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://_samurai_jack.livejournal.com/"&gt;_samurai_jack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://yazad.livejournal.com/"&gt;yazad&lt;/a&gt; (100 - 150)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://iamneo.livejournal.com/"&gt;iamneo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://themadman.livejournal.com/"&gt;themadman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mansu.livejournal.com/"&gt;mansu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://balaji.livejournal.com/"&gt;balaji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pranav.livejournal.com/"&gt;pranav&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kanishka_sinha.livejournal.com/"&gt;kanishka_sinha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code_martial.livejournal.com/"&gt;code_martial&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jakespeak.livejournal.com/"&gt;jakespeak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aivalli.livejournal.com/"&gt;aivalli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kewldeaf.livejournal.com/"&gt;kewldeaf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://quizling.livejournal.com/"&gt;quizling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mannu.livejournal.com/"&gt;mannu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://basrya.livejournal.com/"&gt;basrya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mohitmantri.livejournal.com/"&gt;mohitmantri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aldrind.livejournal.com/"&gt;aldrind&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://abhisheks.livejournal.com/"&gt;abhisheks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vighy.livejournal.com/"&gt;vighy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://adityasn.livejournal.com/"&gt;adityasn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vaibhavtelang.livejournal.com/"&gt;vaibhavtelang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amitporwal.livejournal.com/"&gt;amitporwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arunshanbhag.livejournal.com/"&gt;arunshanbhag&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eh_donia.livejournal.com/"&gt;eh_donia&lt;/a&gt; (150 - 200)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kalyan.livejournal.com/"&gt;kalyan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://teemus.livejournal.com/"&gt;teemus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eddd.livejournal.com/"&gt;eddd&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kaustubhhere.livejournal.com/"&gt;kaustubhhere&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://manish.livejournal.com/"&gt;manish&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://deelight.livejournal.com/"&gt;deelight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://azooey.livejournal.com/"&gt;azooey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ravi.livejournal.com/"&gt;ravi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sharat.livejournal.com/"&gt;sharat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sushil.livejournal.com/"&gt;sushil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://urmila.livejournal.com/"&gt;urmila&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jackol.livejournal.com/"&gt;jackol&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://navindhanuka.livejournal.com/"&gt;navindhanuka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://astra1111.livejournal.com/"&gt;astra1111&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tariquesani.livejournal.com/"&gt;tariquesani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nash_da_basher.livejournal.com/"&gt;nash_da_basher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aish11.livejournal.com/"&gt;aish11&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sampada.livejournal.com/"&gt;sampada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bhavanar.livejournal.com/"&gt;bhavanar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://puremeteor.livejournal.com/"&gt;puremeteor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://_dodo_.livejournal.com/"&gt;_dodo_&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://venus_zulfaris.livejournal.com/"&gt;venus_zulfaris&lt;/a&gt; (200 - 250)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hazeldusk.livejournal.com/"&gt;hazeldusk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kashyapp.livejournal.com/"&gt;kashyapp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rukma.livejournal.com/"&gt;rukma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://biswarup.livejournal.com/"&gt;biswarup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://minn.livejournal.com/"&gt;minn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://avantika.livejournal.com/"&gt;avantika&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://radhika74.livejournal.com/"&gt;radhika74&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mekin.livejournal.com/"&gt;mekin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jessyleen.livejournal.com/"&gt;jessyleen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://psychicsizzler.livejournal.com/"&gt;psychicsizzler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://virtuallyundone.livejournal.com/"&gt;virtuallyundone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bluesmuse.livejournal.com/"&gt;bluesmuse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aneeta_04.livejournal.com/"&gt;aneeta_04&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nvivek.livejournal.com/"&gt;nvivek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://the_little_sasi.livejournal.com/"&gt;the_little_sasi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vivekm.livejournal.com/"&gt;vivekm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jangid.livejournal.com/"&gt;jangid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jojukavalan.livejournal.com/"&gt;jojukavalan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rao_sandeep.livejournal.com/"&gt;rao_sandeep&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://petropeter.livejournal.com/"&gt;petropeter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://quickgun_kc.livejournal.com/"&gt;quickgun_kc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://shantanoo.livejournal.com/"&gt;shantanoo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://roymethos.livejournal.com/"&gt;roymethos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brainz.livejournal.com/"&gt;brainz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://luv_serendipity.livejournal.com/"&gt;luv_serendipity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mmk.livejournal.com/"&gt;mmk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pratibha75.livejournal.com/"&gt;pratibha75&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2fargon.livejournal.com/"&gt;2fargon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://udhay.livejournal.com/"&gt;udhay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://klooloola.livejournal.com/"&gt;klooloola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://suku.livejournal.com/"&gt;suku&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://oivas.livejournal.com/"&gt;oivas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://anilash.livejournal.com/"&gt;anilash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://achitnis.livejournal.com/"&gt;achitnis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://yathin.livejournal.com/"&gt;yathin&lt;/a&gt; (250 - 300)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://irq2.livejournal.com/"&gt;irq2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://notanangel78.livejournal.com/"&gt;notanangel78&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rileen.livejournal.com/"&gt;rileen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://botsie.livejournal.com/"&gt;botsie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://beatzo.livejournal.com/"&gt;beatzo&lt;/a&gt; (300 - 350)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created by ciphergoth; hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lshift.net/"&gt;LShift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://trustflow.lshift.net/?src=sameerds"&gt;TrustFlow II: Who is closest to your friends
list?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="meme"></category><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>break that chain ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/07/20/break-that-chain/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-07-20T10:19:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-07-20T10:19:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-07-20:/2006/07/20/break-that-chain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As usual, the day begins with checking email, visiting slashdot, and skimming through various RSS feeds. In the middle of all that yesterday, received one mail too many about some new hard disk killer virus that can affect you if you add some particular ID on orkut. So dashed off …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As usual, the day begins with checking email, visiting slashdot, and skimming through various RSS feeds. In the middle of all that yesterday, received one mail too many about some new hard disk killer virus that can affect you if you add some particular ID on orkut. So dashed off a quick reprisal and a little bit of advice to Mr. Friendly-neighbourhood-fanatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mail, which:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1) is forwarded by friends &amp;quot;just out of care&amp;quot;, especially those that are not really &amp;quot;computer-masters&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2) asks you to &amp;quot;tell everyone&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3) makes vague claims such as &amp;quot;hard drive killer&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;very horrible virus&amp;quot; without mentioning useful technical details&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;4) says that this was found &amp;quot;last Saturday&amp;quot;, which does not mean any particular date&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;5) gives no reference to an actual (real, verifiable) security warning by some reliable agency such as one of the anti-virus vendors or the affected site itself&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is guaranteed to be a stupid hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from the first characteristic, if the answer is yes, then you can assume its a hoax, without checking further characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="netizens"></category></entry><entry><title>as if!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/07/11/as-if/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-07-11T11:29:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-07-11T11:29:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-07-11:/2006/07/11/as-if/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just to make a point, I use a Colgate medium toothbrush and Pepsodent two-in-one toothpaste. If I use just white paste, the &amp;quot;fresh breath&amp;quot; doesn't stay around for too long; if I use gel, the teeth don't feel so nice by afternoon! So I prefer Pepsodent 2-in-1, or a DIY …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just to make a point, I use a Colgate medium toothbrush and Pepsodent two-in-one toothpaste. If I use just white paste, the &amp;quot;fresh breath&amp;quot; doesn't stay around for too long; if I use gel, the teeth don't feel so nice by afternoon! So I prefer Pepsodent 2-in-1, or a DIY combination. And due to gross mismanagement of resources, I actually have three toothbrushes at my Powai home, two at my parents' place in Thane, and one at my aunt's place in Pune!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there. I put it online. It's official now. Some people actually think that shallow sarcasm is going to get them anywhere! Boston Brahmins are crazy, I say.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="blarg"></category></entry><entry><title>change of status ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/07/10/change-of-status/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-07-10T09:50:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-07-10T09:50:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-07-10:/2006/07/10/change-of-status/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hmmm ... been absconding long enough now, I suppose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Wedding - done.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;HoneyMoon - done.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Shifting to new house - done.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Current status:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Completed two weeks of naya &amp;quot;sansar&amp;quot; (that's marathi for &amp;quot;ghar-grihasthi&amp;quot;).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Also completed ten days of managing the house on our own, with no parental guidance.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Raves:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;New front-loading, 7kg, Siemens 2002XL …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hmmm ... been absconding long enough now, I suppose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Wedding - done.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;HoneyMoon - done.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Shifting to new house - done.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Current status:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Completed two weeks of naya &amp;quot;sansar&amp;quot; (that's marathi for &amp;quot;ghar-grihasthi&amp;quot;).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Also completed ten days of managing the house on our own, with no parental guidance.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Raves:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;New front-loading, 7kg, Siemens 2002XL washing machine (Made in Turkey) and the bliss of weekly laundry.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Steadily improving cooking skills.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Shopping for groceries and vegetables at Shoprite Hyper.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Rants:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;None yet! ;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;TODO:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Upload photos.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Get back to work ... hmmmm.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="knotty stuff"></category></entry><entry><title>i am (not) that</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/05/18/i-am-not-that/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-05-18T10:40:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-05-18T10:40:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-05-18:/2006/05/18/i-am-not-that/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What better way to start the day than an enlightening mail from your friendly neighbourhood fanatic. This message was truly enlightening ... it en-light-ened my mood to no end ... havn't had such amusing bullshit for breakfast in a long time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Dear Friends,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;Human Genome Project&amp;quot; was an ambitious project to map …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What better way to start the day than an enlightening mail from your friendly neighbourhood fanatic. This message was truly enlightening ... it en-light-ened my mood to no end ... havn't had such amusing bullshit for breakfast in a long time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Dear Friends,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;Human Genome Project&amp;quot; was an ambitious project to map the genes of various communities of Humans. But as was speculated earlier, this project turned out to be used for various socio-politico-psychological purposes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now they have concluded that&amp;quot;Human Ancestors May Have Interbred With Chimpanzees&amp;quot; , check the link &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2006/05/17/AR2006051702158.html"&gt;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2006/05/17/AR2006051702158.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My firm opinion is that this may be the history or past of the medieval ancestors of Euro-Americo-African people, but definitely not of Indians. We are born out of Rishis, Munis, which are indicated by our Gotra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its my strong request to the Governments of US, UK etc that the &amp;quot;Darwins Theory and the present THEORY PROJECTED BY Genome Project &amp;quot; which tries to prove that humans have element of &amp;quot;Monkeys&amp;quot; due to the secret indulgence with Monkeys may be taught to their students of their respective nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are born out of cultured Rishis ( Thats our Rich and Vatican Bothering Identity)so they may not try to harm our indentity by preaching their so called findings of Genetic Project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Da Vinci Code can bother even the Central Government of India ... I think the display of this theory on Indian Internet and Indian journals should also bother our Central Government. Even the Christian members should oppose this theory since it goes against the Bible. And Muslims too should be irked due to this theory because if they get troubled by the cartoon of Mohammad ... what should they do in case the Genome Project theory says the Humans have interbred and have elements of Monkey... so if they do not oppose this theory .. even Mohammed may come under this theory ... again going against Koran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am surprised as to why Vatican is quite in this matter .... the Vatican Silence on this issue points to something &amp;quot;Daal Mein Kaala&amp;quot; ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wont even mind if they tell their students that they are ancestors of whatever monkey or donkey .. we would even believe the theory if they say it about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends we should be aware of these slow-poisoning and Identity - Destroying strategies of west.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Yours&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(undisclosed)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="blarg"></category></entry><entry><title>tail, swallow</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/05/02/tail-swallow/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-05-02T07:44:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-05-02T07:44:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-05-02:/2006/05/02/tail-swallow/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Self reference! Ah, I can see that I made you sit up and take notice. So you thought you liked &amp;quot;Adaptation&amp;quot;? Wait till you take a look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.math.uchicago.edu/~chruska/recursive/selfref.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. But read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.math.uchicago.edu/~chruska/recursive/moser.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; before you read that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, the tag for this entry is &amp;quot;MLP&amp;quot; which stands for &amp;quot;Mindless Link Propagation …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Self reference! Ah, I can see that I made you sit up and take notice. So you thought you liked &amp;quot;Adaptation&amp;quot;? Wait till you take a look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.math.uchicago.edu/~chruska/recursive/selfref.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. But read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.math.uchicago.edu/~chruska/recursive/moser.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; before you read that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, the tag for this entry is &amp;quot;MLP&amp;quot; which stands for &amp;quot;Mindless Link Propagation&amp;quot;, first seen on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kuro5hin.org"&gt;http://kuro5hin.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="mlp"></category></entry><entry><title>staying put</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/04/18/staying-put/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-04-18T10:22:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-04-18T10:22:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-04-18:/2006/04/18/staying-put/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=183316&amp;amp;cid=15142369"&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/04/17/1350239"&gt;slashdot article&lt;/a&gt; about Oracle thinking of buying Novell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You overreacted. KDE is still very much supported on SuSE. Why jump ship based on a rumour of what someone might possibly do when you can just as easily jump ship later if they ever actually do …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=183316&amp;amp;cid=15142369"&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/04/17/1350239"&gt;slashdot article&lt;/a&gt; about Oracle thinking of buying Novell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You overreacted. KDE is still very much supported on SuSE. Why jump ship based on a rumour of what someone might possibly do when you can just as easily jump ship later if they ever actually do it. I am on OpenSuSE 10.0 now and the water is just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I was worried that what I was doing did not have much of a future and was looking at retraining doing something else. In the end I decided to carry on with what I was already specialised in and cross that bridge (retraining) when I came to it. I am still working on the same platform 20 years later, still worried that it is going to run out at some point but have noticed that some of the alternatives I was looking at back then no longer exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice advice, really. Would fit right in with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://paulgraham.com/hs.html"&gt;list of things that you wish you were told when you were a kid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="don't panic, free software, life"></category><category term="hacked"></category></entry><entry><title>vanquishing ghosts ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/04/12/vanquishing-ghosts/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-04-12T09:03:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-04-12T09:03:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-04-12:/2006/04/12/vanquishing-ghosts/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a run-in with a ghost very early this morning ... and I won!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been a frequent problem with me actually, that when I fall asleep, I am quite likely to be lying in a contorted position, with some strain on the neck and shoulders. The result is blocked blood …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a run-in with a ghost very early this morning ... and I won!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been a frequent problem with me actually, that when I fall asleep, I am quite likely to be lying in a contorted position, with some strain on the neck and shoulders. The result is blocked blood flow to the head some time later (or at least that's what I think it is). And then my brain starts playing games with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am usually half awake at this point ... I can see and hear things around me, but try as I might, I can't move my limbs and nor can I wake up. Then I start seeing things that aren't really there - familiar things take on new shapes, and some of the shapes take on faces. Trying to wake up in this situation is the most difficult part. It's rather painful too, with your head throbbing, and your heart responding to some kinda fear of those unseen things. Being fully aware of my state, I go to great lengths to try and wake up ... I even tried calling the guy in the next room once, on the cellphone, so that he could come and wake me up. But since there was no motor control, that didn't work out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was one such morning. It started as a dream, but eventually I realised I am in my own room. The trouser hanging by a hook on the wall had sprouted half limbs and a rather scary face, and was trying to talk to me. I tried to tell it that I know what's happening and I am not afraid, but that didn't really help. Then I decided to do something that I had not done before. I closed my eyes and ignored it!!! Next thing I know, I am asleep and I wake up fully in a few minutes. At least, I guess it was just a few minutes, since the light at dawn hadn't changed much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always wondered how many ghost stories must have originated in remote villages, before there were vehicles, when people had to cross jungles on foot. All it takes is a person sleeping on a protruding root of a tree in the wrong position, and the whole jungle comes alive around him!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="don't panic"></category><category term="ghosts"></category></entry><entry><title>42 ... found, and found again!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/29/42-found-and-found-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-29T22:53:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-29T22:53:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-29:/2006/03/29/42-found-and-found-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A rather interesting new &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.orkut.com/CommMsgs.aspx?cmm=3320&amp;amp;tid=17867936&amp;amp;start=1"&gt;conversation&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.orkut.com/Community.aspx?cmm=3320"&gt;Don't Panic&lt;/a&gt; community on ` &amp;lt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.orkut.com/"&gt;http://www.orkut.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;`__Orkut talks about worldly occurences of the ultimate answer ... a compilation found &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ambrish.de/answer_to_the_ultimate_question_.htm"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one takes the cake:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LaTeX book (1st edition) by Leslie Lamport makes a reference to 42 while discussing the use …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A rather interesting new &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.orkut.com/CommMsgs.aspx?cmm=3320&amp;amp;tid=17867936&amp;amp;start=1"&gt;conversation&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.orkut.com/Community.aspx?cmm=3320"&gt;Don't Panic&lt;/a&gt; community on ` &amp;lt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.orkut.com/"&gt;http://www.orkut.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;`__Orkut talks about worldly occurences of the ultimate answer ... a compilation found &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ambrish.de/answer_to_the_ultimate_question_.htm"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one takes the cake:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LaTeX book (1st edition) by Leslie Lamport makes a reference to 42 while discussing the use of references and labels. Its says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;See page 42 for more details.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Text on page 42:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The meaning of life, the universe, and ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="farts"></category></entry><entry><title>punyanagari and back ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/23/punyanagari-and-back/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-23T10:26:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-23T10:26:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-23:/2006/03/23/punyanagari-and-back/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back from a quick visit to Pune, meeting up with a couple of friends and scouting for wedding garments. First thing I noticed was the huge number of huge malls coming up ... mostly in Koregaon Park, M. G. Road and such areas. We walked into what seemed to be Shoppers's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back from a quick visit to Pune, meeting up with a couple of friends and scouting for wedding garments. First thing I noticed was the huge number of huge malls coming up ... mostly in Koregaon Park, M. G. Road and such areas. We walked into what seemed to be Shoppers's Stop at the junction opposite the Blue Nile, but when we got out from the other side, we realised it was a mall called Nucleus, that takes up an entire small block!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some quick updates about Pune:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pune edition of TOI still publishes small stories from the previous day's Mumbai edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="upperalpha simple" start="13"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;ol class="first upperalpha" start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road will be a Wi-Fi hotspot starting from 25th March. The service will be free for a 90-day trial period, after which, users will have to register and pay. The papers are fully of assuarances that the whole of Pune city will have wireless services within a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authorities want to commit infrastructure to make Pune the IT hub of the future. But IT heads in Pune itself want them to concentrate on Pune's civic infrastructure instead, since that, along with some decent publicity will benefit the IT industry in Pune in far better ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fly-over near University continues to be delayed. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amunix.livejournal.com/"&gt;amunix&lt;/a&gt; says the delay is supposedly due to the sewage, drains, telecom cables etc, that need to be relocated. The respective departments are asking for more time, because they don't know their locations. The POA seems to be: &amp;quot;locate and relocate&amp;quot; :) ... with appropriate side-effects, of course!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="pune"></category><category term="shopping"></category></entry><entry><title>and then he was gone ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/17/and-then-he-was-gone/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-17T09:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-17T09:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-17:/2006/03/17/and-then-he-was-gone/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;... today morning, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world rearranged itself slightly. Yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So long, dude! And thanks for all the fish. [STRIKEOUT:Really] &lt;em&gt;Literally&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;... today morning, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world rearranged itself slightly. Yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So long, dude! And thanks for all the fish. [STRIKEOUT:Really] &lt;em&gt;Literally&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Ramble on, RMS!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/11/ramble-on-rms/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-11T16:11:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-11T16:11:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-11:/2006/03/11/ramble-on-rms/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took the title of this entry from a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=179845&amp;amp;cid=14893407"&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on slashdot. The comment is attached to a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/03/10/1735205"&gt;slashdot article&lt;/a&gt; about an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.forbes.com/technology/2006/03/09/torvalds-linux-licensing-cz_dl_0309torvalds1.html"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; of Linus Torvalds regarding the GPLv3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not followed the developments about the GPLv3, and to be honest ignored it as yet some more &amp;quot;RMS rambling …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took the title of this entry from a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=179845&amp;amp;cid=14893407"&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on slashdot. The comment is attached to a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/03/10/1735205"&gt;slashdot article&lt;/a&gt; about an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.forbes.com/technology/2006/03/09/torvalds-linux-licensing-cz_dl_0309torvalds1.html"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; of Linus Torvalds regarding the GPLv3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not followed the developments about the GPLv3, and to be honest ignored it as yet some more &amp;quot;RMS rambling&amp;quot;. But the commentary on this feature did manage to make me sit up and at least form an opinion. In the Forbes interview, Linus really has demonstrated how irresponsible he can get about philosophy. There is a lot of serious thought that's going into the GPLv3, the same kind that must have happened when RMS first put his foot down against the rise of non-free software, and at the drafting of the first GPL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linus' devil-may-care attitude had always bugged me, including his choice of BitKeeper. But this interview shows exactly how off the track he is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
If you have a device that has software in it (and most devices do, these days), the FSF wants normal users to be able to upgrade that software. Now, sometimes it's simply not technically possible. But sometimes the software can be upgraded, but the hardware limits it on purpose so that the owner of the hardware cannot do so--only the vendor can. I think that's pretty nasty myself. I much prefer things that can be fixed. However, I don't think that's part of my GPLv2 contract. I'd rather vote with my personal choices (and my dollars) than by trying to make my software be a &amp;quot;weapon of mass opinion.&amp;quot; And I just care a lot more about some things than I do about others (I would refuse to buy a computer that I can't replace the OS on, but a dishwasher or a DVR? Not a huge deal to me).&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just goes to show he is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a community leader. But I must give him points for being downright honest about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Another way of saying the same thing: I don't want to make my software be &amp;quot;activist.&amp;quot; I try to make it technically as good as possible and let that part speak for itself. I don't want it to make politics.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last I checked, anything that affected &lt;em&gt;freedom&lt;/em&gt; is automatically under &lt;em&gt;politics&lt;/em&gt;. For me FLOSS has never been solely about the software itself. It's been about the freedom and the community that is bound together by that freedom. Thank you Mr. Torvalds, but now I know that if someone asks me to name a &amp;quot;leader&amp;quot; in the community, you sure won't be anywhere near the top of the list. I do respect the way Linus has managed the kernel development process to bring it so far, but then again, I also respect Bill Gates for the software giant that he created and helped grow.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="free software, life"></category><category term="hacked"></category></entry><entry><title>no more kernel traffic ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/10/no-more-kernel-traffic/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-10T10:25:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-10T10:25:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-10:/2006/03/10/no-more-kernel-traffic/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kerneltraffic.org/kernel-traffic/latest.html"&gt;http://kerneltraffic.org/kernel-traffic/latest.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovered today that KT has gone inactive now. I had stopped visiting the site after I noticed it hadn't been updated for weeks. Zack says he's taking a break, but the last sentence sounds rather ominous ... &amp;quot;Hopefully Kernel Traffic will not be missed too …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kerneltraffic.org/kernel-traffic/latest.html"&gt;http://kerneltraffic.org/kernel-traffic/latest.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovered today that KT has gone inactive now. I had stopped visiting the site after I noticed it hadn't been updated for weeks. Zack says he's taking a break, but the last sentence sounds rather ominous ... &amp;quot;Hopefully Kernel Traffic will not be missed too greatly, with these other useful resources available.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bye Zack! May the source be with you. You've been a great help to ring-side viewers like me who needed to keep an eye on the kernel but didn't have enough time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's sites like KT run by Zack Brown and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.kuro5hin.org/?op=special;page=mission"&gt;Kuro5hin&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.kuro5hin.org/?op=special;page=random#rusty"&gt;Rusty&lt;/a&gt; that remind me of how lazy I really am.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="free software"></category><category term="idle thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>vodka delight</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/09/vodka-delight/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-09T22:26:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-09T22:26:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-09:/2006/03/09/vodka-delight/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I tasted Fuel, the new Vodka on the block, it has pretty much replaced Romanov as well as Smirnoff as the drink of choice for me. These days, most quarter bars accessible from IIT have Fuel, although it hasn't showed up in Thane yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I don't …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I tasted Fuel, the new Vodka on the block, it has pretty much replaced Romanov as well as Smirnoff as the drink of choice for me. These days, most quarter bars accessible from IIT have Fuel, although it hasn't showed up in Thane yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I don't drink anymore ... I &amp;quot;ReFuel&amp;quot; :D&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="farts"></category><category term="quarter"></category></entry><entry><title>Guest Book</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/06/guest-book/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-06T10:09:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-06T10:09:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-06:/2006/03/06/guest-book/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In case you decide to say &amp;quot;hi&amp;quot; ...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In case you decide to say &amp;quot;hi&amp;quot; ...&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>engaging warp drive!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/04/engaging-warp-drive/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-04T12:22:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-04T12:22:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-04:/2006/03/04/engaging-warp-drive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finished watching the end of Season 2 for Star Trek DS9 ... what a way to end the season! (or to get started, actually ...) Found a nice line on the net describing the episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;The Jem'Hadar&amp;quot; is an intelligent, powerful episode that reveals all--and nothing--about the Dominion.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="quark" src="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/%7Esameerds/eris.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="17%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="83%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sisko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;You're one of …&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finished watching the end of Season 2 for Star Trek DS9 ... what a way to end the season! (or to get started, actually ...) Found a nice line on the net describing the episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;The Jem'Hadar&amp;quot; is an intelligent, powerful episode that reveals all--and nothing--about the Dominion.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="quark" src="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/%7Esameerds/eris.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="17%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="83%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sisko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;You're one of the Founders, aren't you?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eris:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;You think the Founders would waste their time with you?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sisko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Constable!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Odo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Madam, if you'll come with us ...&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eris:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;You have no idea what's begun here (transports)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sisko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chief!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O'Brian:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I am picking up a transporter signature but I can't trace it.
She didn't remateriliaze anywhere on the station, and there are no
ships near by.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bashir:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Then where is she?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kira:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;She'll be back; question is, who she'll bring with her.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sisko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(camera zooms slowly, intense drama :) If the Dominion comes
through the worm-hole, the first battle will be fought here. And I
intend to be ready for them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content><category term="ds9"></category><category term="sci-fi"></category><category term="star trek"></category></entry><entry><title>LJ gimmicks</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/02/lj-gimmicks/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-02T17:52:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-02T17:52:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-02:/2006/03/02/lj-gimmicks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I realised using the &amp;quot;lj-cut&amp;quot; tag is a rather bad idea ... why force people to click on &amp;quot;Read more&amp;quot; when they can simply scroll and go on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, no more &amp;quot;lj-cut&amp;quot; from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I realised using the &amp;quot;lj-cut&amp;quot; tag is a rather bad idea ... why force people to click on &amp;quot;Read more&amp;quot; when they can simply scroll and go on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, no more &amp;quot;lj-cut&amp;quot; from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>DS9 surprise ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/02/ds9-surprise/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-02T15:26:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-02T15:26:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-02:/2006/03/02/ds9-surprise/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had initially been rather skeptical about Star Trek - Deep Space 9 ... but well into the second season, I am beginning to like it! Quite different from the other Star Trek story-lines, the characters in this one come in all hues and shades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was particularly amused by one scene from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had initially been rather skeptical about Star Trek - Deep Space 9 ... but well into the second season, I am beginning to like it! Quite different from the other Star Trek story-lines, the characters in this one come in all hues and shades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was particularly amused by one scene from an episode I watched today, that introduces the Maqui ... we see Quark, the Firangi bartender on DS9, explaining war in terms of business to Sakonna, a Vulcan member of the Maqui&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="quark" src="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/quark.png" /&gt; &lt;img alt="sakonna" src="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/sakonna.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="20%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="80%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Now ... the Third Rule clearly states that &amp;quot;never
spend more for an acquisition, than you have to.&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sakonna:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Logical, but I fail to see how that applies to my
situation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;You want to acquire peace. Fine. Peace is good.
But, how much're you willing to pay for it?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sakonna:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Whatever it costs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;That's the kind of irresponsible spending that
causes so many business ventures to fail. You're
forgetting the Third Rule. Right now, peace could be
bought at a bargain price, and you don't even realise
it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sakonna:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I find this very confusing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;harrr ... then I'll make it so simple that even a
Vulcan can understand.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content><category term="ds9"></category><category term="sci-fi"></category><category term="star trek"></category></entry><entry><title>successful software?</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/03/02/successful-software/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-02T10:01:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-03-02T10:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-03-02:/2006/03/02/successful-software/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted a comment on 's journal, and this is what LJ reported:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comment Posted Successfully&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successfully? Somebody at LJ-dot-org not confident enough about support for comments in LJ yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then when I post this entry, here's what it says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updating journal&lt;/strong&gt;... Update successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can bloody well &lt;em&gt;see …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted a comment on 's journal, and this is what LJ reported:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comment Posted Successfully&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successfully? Somebody at LJ-dot-org not confident enough about support for comments in LJ yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then when I post this entry, here's what it says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updating journal&lt;/strong&gt;... Update successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can bloody well &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; it's been updated, thank you! Could you please take me to my journal's front page instead?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="nitpicks"></category></entry><entry><title>worry for nothing, advice for free</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/02/24/worry-for-nothing-advice-for-free/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-02-24T16:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-02-24T16:36:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-02-24:/2006/02/24/worry-for-nothing-advice-for-free/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To get things up to date, first &amp;quot;the&amp;quot; announcment - I got &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/snaps/engg/"&gt;engaged on February 5th&lt;/a&gt; to a certain Miss Meenal Phatak from Dombivali. Known her for a year or so ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I told all the near, far, dear and not-so-dear friends about it, there's been a steady trickle of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To get things up to date, first &amp;quot;the&amp;quot; announcment - I got &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/snaps/engg/"&gt;engaged on February 5th&lt;/a&gt; to a certain Miss Meenal Phatak from Dombivali. Known her for a year or so ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I told all the near, far, dear and not-so-dear friends about it, there's been a steady trickle of congratulations, consolations, and of course, advice from the one's who are &amp;quot;on the other side&amp;quot;. That varies from &amp;quot;good for you, dude!&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;enjoy it while you can&amp;quot; and lots of things in between, or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Then there are those with some good-intentioned pointers attached with a claim of &amp;quot;trust me, I've been married for (insert suitable multiple of ten) years!&amp;quot; Here's some rather sound advice from one such friend. I normally hate the idea of expressing every-day things in technical terms, but this one makes the mark really well:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Now a word of advice in engineering (i.e. practical as against abstract-love-language or philosophically nebulous managment way) terms....You will be &amp;quot;in-phase&amp;quot; with Meenal until [after one year] (approx.), then you may start noticing phase lag (who lags whom depends and varies on a situational basis). At that time, your automatic phase locked loop circuit kicks in and the feedback system become stable. Leave some &amp;quot;jitter&amp;quot; in the system as it is needed for the overall stability of the system. Dominant poles don't move much, no matter how good your lock-in mechanism is....and don't kid yourself fretting over who the dominant pole really is (it is more important to know where it is!). As long as you are within about 10 deg. out of phase, the system will be stable all your life. Don't try too hard to be &amp;quot;in-phase&amp;quot; over time because it simply does not work! No detrimental effects of this &amp;quot;out-of-phase&amp;quot; relationship is observed over time. My conclusion is based on 20.5 years of observations of my personal kokanastha system in operation. Everything works out well in time domain as long as the initial conditions and integration limits are well defined.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for that, Dilip! Really hope you are around the day I &amp;quot;cross over&amp;quot; to the other (dark?) side.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="knotty stuff"></category></entry><entry><title>finally, the journal goes live!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2006/02/22/finally-the-journal-goes-live/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-02-22T23:53:00+05:30</published><updated>2006-02-22T23:53:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2006-02-22:/2006/02/22/finally-the-journal-goes-live/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'd always been &amp;quot;left out&amp;quot; of the blogging scene simply because I couldn't get myself around to shift to livejournal. I've been writing rather infrequently on my own site, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Finally, here I am ... on LJ! I had tried command-line clients a year ago, that would help me upload my …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'd always been &amp;quot;left out&amp;quot; of the blogging scene simply because I couldn't get myself around to shift to livejournal. I've been writing rather infrequently on my own site, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Finally, here I am ... on LJ! I had tried command-line clients a year ago, that would help me upload my MySQL based blog to LJ. But I gave up, after some frustrating attempts at batch mode submissions through proxies. This time around, I managed to pull it off in two hours, and I have the time stamps to prove it!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;It's all thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cis.rit.edu/~jerry/Software/perl/#jlj"&gt;JLJ&lt;/a&gt;, the perl based command-line client. It has a nifty queuing system that can upload a bunch of entries from simple-to-edit text files. All it took was a perl script that dumped back-dated entries into serially numbered files. JLJ did its magic after that.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now about the time-stamps ... was chatting with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vipul.livejournal.com/"&gt;vipul&lt;/a&gt; when I re-embarked on this grand endeavour. He discovers that I had created this account exactly two years and one day ago! Co-incidence? Divine plans?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, also pasting a log of our conversation ... a partial account of the events that led to this posting. Makes me feel like Charlie Kaufman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:30:23) sameerds: hey you there?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:30:36) vipulmathur: ya&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:31:04) sameerds: i am back in upload-blog-to-livejournal mode :D&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:31:19) vipulmathur: wah wah&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:31:22) sameerds: thinking of trying out the command line clients and see if any of them can work in batch mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:31:36) vipulmathur: interesting :)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:31:38) sameerds: so i can dump my own blog entries and put them up backdated on livejournal&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:31:50) vipulmathur: ya.. good idea&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:31:59) sameerds: thought i should do a quick check and see if you've heard of a way&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:32:15) vipulmathur: might want to look at some of the gui clients as well... they might have an &amp;quot;import&amp;quot; feature&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:32:29) vipulmathur: dunno of any exact one though&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:32:53) sameerds: ok JLJ seems to have an offline mode, and the release file says the &amp;quot;queue file&amp;quot; is documented&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:32:58) sameerds: maybe that's all i'll need&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:33:06) sameerds: stay tuned for updates B-)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:33:45) vipulmathur: :) kewl&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:33:51) vipulmathur: keep me posted&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:33:56) vipulmathur: btw lj user=?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:34:08) sameerds: sameerds&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:34:13) sameerds: unused so far&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:34:16) vipulmathur: :&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:34:26) sameerds: why the naughty smile?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:35:07) vipulmathur: lucky you&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:36:18) sameerds: ??&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:36:27) sameerds: oh because i got my default id, is it?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:36:33) vipulmathur: ya duh&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:36:36) vipulmathur: :)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:36:40) vipulmathur: how about trantor5&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:36:44) vipulmathur: its free too&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:36:49) vipulmathur: :D&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:37:22) sameerds: hehe&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:37:44) sameerds: sounds nice actually ... my online handle, if i ever use it, is actually &amp;quot;ashant&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:38:12) vipulmathur: hmm... :-?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:48:23) sameerds: it woiked it woiked&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:48:34) sameerds: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sameerds.livejournal.com/"&gt;http://sameerds.livejournal.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:48:34) vipulmathur: =D&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:48:41) vipulmathur: already there :)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:48:44) sameerds: a back-date entry in batch mode!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:49:01) sameerds: now all i need is a script to dump my blog in the original format&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:49:31) vipulmathur: I just saw the transition from &amp;quot;updated 59 weeks ago&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;updated 48 seconds ago&amp;quot; :D&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:49:37) sameerds: hehe&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:50:16) vipulmathur: so has the dream come true? :&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:50:42) vipulmathur: [Feb. 22nd, 2005|09:42 pm] it says&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:51:36) sameerds: right&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:52:06) sameerds: one more entry ... just checking if renaming the queue files works ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:52:34) sameerds: hmmm ... now its time for perl, and perldb ... since my blog is in mysql&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:52:57) vipulmathur: hmm&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:53:55) vipulmathur: you created your LJ account 1 year and one day + delta ago?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:54:02) vipulmathur: oops 2 years&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:54:21) sameerds: why do you reckon that?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:54:35) sameerds: because of the entry?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:55:06) sameerds: &amp;quot;last updated 59 weeks ago&amp;quot; ... remember?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:55:26) sameerds: that entry i made was just a try at back dating ... changed the year for a new test entry in the queue&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:55:45) vipulmathur: ya but 59 weeks == 1 year+ some weeks&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:55:50) sameerds: oh ok&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:55:52) sameerds: yeah&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:56:09) vipulmathur: Date created:2004-02-21 03:49:21Date updated:2006-02-22 16:21:32, 1 minute ago&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:56:11) sameerds: 1 year, one month and some more&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:56:16) sameerds: oh cool&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:56:20) sameerds: amazing! :D&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:56:24) vipulmathur: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sameerds.livejournal.com/profile?mode=full"&gt;http://sameerds.livejournal.com/profile?mode=full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:56:31) vipulmathur: is that a co-incidence :O&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:56:45) vipulmathur: I mean the 2 year thing&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:57:00) sameerds: it sure is! good matter for my first &amp;quot;fresh&amp;quot; blog entry, eh?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:57:14) vipulmathur: you bet!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:57:27) sameerds: time for an FLab-style night out now ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:57:37) vipulmathur: he he :D&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:58:18) sameerds: hell ... i am going to post this conversation itself ... reminds me of that movie ... &amp;quot;adaptation&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:58:31) sameerds: the one about the book about the orchids&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:58:41) sameerds: nicholas cage in a double role&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(21:59:25) vipulmathur: yo&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;(22:00:05) enjoy it dude! may the source be with you!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>The crownless shall be king ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2005/05/07/the-crownless-shall-be-king/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-05-07T21:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2005-05-07T21:48:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2005-05-07:/2005/05/07/the-crownless-shall-be-king/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nothing has been as memorable as discovering Tolkien's &amp;quot;Lord of the Rings&amp;quot; trilogy when I first joined IIT! I have read it quite a few times already ... savouring the excellent language and the elegant descriptions. Got my own copy back in my hands after being circulated among a few friends …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nothing has been as memorable as discovering Tolkien's &amp;quot;Lord of the Rings&amp;quot; trilogy when I first joined IIT! I have read it quite a few times already ... savouring the excellent language and the elegant descriptions. Got my own copy back in my hands after being circulated among a few friends. How I wish I could go back to the time when I first came across it, and read it &amp;quot;again for the first time!&amp;quot; ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Transcribing my favourite passage in the whole book ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In rode the lord of the Nazgul. A great black shape against the fires beyond he loomed up, grown to a vast menace of despair. In rode the lord of the Nazgul, under the archway that no enemy ever yet had passed, and all fled before his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All save one. There waiting, silent and still in the space before the Gate, sat Gandalf upon Shadowfax: Shadowfax who alone among the free horses of the earth endured the terror, unmoving, steadfast as a graven image in Rath Dinen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'You cannot enter here,' said Gandalf, and the huge shadow halted. 'Go back to the abyss prepared for you! Go back! Fall into the nothingness that awaits you and your Master. Go!'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Black Rider flung back his hood, and behold! he had a kingly crown; and yet upon no head visible was it set. The red fires shone between it and the mantled shoulders vast and dark. From a mouth unseen there came a deadly laughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Old fool!' he said. 'Old fool! This is my hour. Do you not know Death when you see it? Die now and curse in vain!' And with that he lifted high his sword and flames ran down the blade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gandalf did not move. And in that very moment, away behind in some courtyard of the City, a cock crowed. Shrill and clear he crowed, recking nothing of wizardry or war, welcoming only the morning that in the sky far above the shadows of death was coming with the dawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as if in answer there came from far away another note. Horns, horns, horns. In dark Mindolluin's sides they dimly echoed. Great horns of the North wildly blowing. Rohan had come at last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="reading"></category></entry><entry><title>wiki wiki!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2005/01/14/wiki-wiki/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-01-14T22:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2005-01-14T22:34:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2005-01-14:/2005/01/14/wiki-wiki/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Just thought I should note that I finally settled for a sane and simple design on my website. No wiki, for managing it, just plain old php scripts edited by hand. But I do use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.splitbrain.org/dokuwiki/wiki:dokuwiki"&gt;DokuWiki&lt;/a&gt; for maintaining my notes. Also &lt;a class="reference external" href="/~sameerds/wiki/doku.php"&gt;experimenting&lt;/a&gt; with some enhanchements of my own.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;What I …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Just thought I should note that I finally settled for a sane and simple design on my website. No wiki, for managing it, just plain old php scripts edited by hand. But I do use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.splitbrain.org/dokuwiki/wiki:dokuwiki"&gt;DokuWiki&lt;/a&gt; for maintaining my notes. Also &lt;a class="reference external" href="/~sameerds/wiki/doku.php"&gt;experimenting&lt;/a&gt; with some enhanchements of my own.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;What I learnt from my experiments with PhpWiki&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never use a hammer to drive a loose screw!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The trouble was that I wanted a wiki for two different purposes - as a&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;CMS for my website, and as a means to make notes. But PhpWiki is meant for&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;neither - I don't know what it's specifically good for, but it certainly&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;didn't serve my purpose!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Finally I learnt it the hard way - if you want to get work done in a simple&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;way, use a simple tool! Also if you want a simple homepage with just basic info&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;in it, build the damn thing yourself. And again, use simple tools ... like&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Personal Weblog and Gallery and DokuWiki.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Of what use ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2005/01/04/of-what-use/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-01-04T14:25:00+05:30</published><updated>2005-01-04T14:25:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2005-01-04:/2005/01/04/of-what-use/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Quite a coincidence that in the midst of a yahoogroup thread about research, its uses, prevalent practices, etc I happened to read an essay by Isaac Asimov, in a non-fiction collection called &amp;quot;The Beginning and the End&amp;quot;. This essay was originally published as the introduction to a book published some …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Quite a coincidence that in the midst of a yahoogroup thread about research, its uses, prevalent practices, etc I happened to read an essay by Isaac Asimov, in a non-fiction collection called &amp;quot;The Beginning and the End&amp;quot;. This essay was originally published as the introduction to a book published some time in the 1960s titled &amp;quot;Of what use&amp;quot;. Pasting the beginning and concluding paragraphs:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
It is the fate of the scientist to face the constant demand that he show his learning to have some &amp;quot;practical use.&amp;quot; Yet it may not be of any interest to him to have such a &amp;quot;practical use&amp;quot; exist; he may feel that the delight of learning, of understanding, of probing the Universe is its own reward entirely. In that case he may even allow himself the indulgence of contempt for anyone who asks more.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he goes on to describe instances in the works of Plato, Faraday, Edison, Einstein etc ... discoveries that either their contemporaries or they themselves ignored as &amp;quot;useless&amp;quot;, but later laid the foundations of modern technology. Obscure discoveries like the &amp;quot;Edison Effect&amp;quot; which was a by-product of the first electric lamp, and on which is based the whole domain of electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally he says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one knows what's in it for you right now, any more than Plato knew in his time or Faraday knew, or Edison knew, or Einstein knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you will know if you live long enough; and if not, your children or grandchildren will know. And they will smile at those who say, &amp;quot;But what is the use of sending rockets into space?&amp;quot; just as we now smile at the person who asked Faraday the use of his demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, unles we continue with science and gather knowledge, whether it is seemingly useful on the spot or not, we will be buried under our problems and find no way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is up to you then, and up to everyone, to support science and, where possible, to keep abreast of it, for today's science is tomorrow's solution - and tomorrow's problems, too - and most of all, mankind's greatest adventure, now and forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="life"></category><category term="hacked"></category></entry><entry><title>Irritating English</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2004/12/28/irritating-english/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-12-28T14:57:00+05:30</published><updated>2004-12-28T14:57:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2004-12-28:/2004/12/28/irritating-english/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;At the outset, here's the mandatory disclaimer: &amp;quot;I am not an &lt;em&gt;expert in English&lt;/em&gt;. I am not the &lt;em&gt;smartest&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;wisest&lt;/em&gt; or the most &lt;em&gt;experienced&lt;/em&gt; literary critic in the world. I am just a humble engineer, but I believe I have a grasp on English that is good enough …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;At the outset, here's the mandatory disclaimer: &amp;quot;I am not an &lt;em&gt;expert in English&lt;/em&gt;. I am not the &lt;em&gt;smartest&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;wisest&lt;/em&gt; or the most &lt;em&gt;experienced&lt;/em&gt; literary critic in the world. I am just a humble engineer, but I believe I have a grasp on English that is good enough for me to recognise a few standard mistakes, especially by the vernie types. I hope that someone out there reads this list, and actually finds it helpful, rather than just deciding I am a snob.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here goes ... it's a list of mistakes in the way people speak English that I find extremely irritating. In fact I can easily lose my chain of thought when I come across one of these mistakes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-present-continuous-tense"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The present continuous tense&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most irritating sentence construction, that is a side-effect of the &amp;quot;think native, talk English&amp;quot; paradigm. A good example is &amp;quot;I &lt;em&gt;am having&lt;/em&gt; a problem.&amp;quot; What's wrong with this? The tense should have been the present perfect: &amp;quot;I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; a problem.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usage &amp;quot;am having&amp;quot; kinda reminds of someone eating something ... as if &amp;quot;I &lt;em&gt;am having&lt;/em&gt; a problem for dinner!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIP: Whenever you need to use the verb &amp;quot;have&amp;quot;, think of the immortal sentence: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0112384/"&gt;&amp;quot;Houston, we have a problem!&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-article"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another commonly occouring problem with the sentence above ... the article! Articles are the words &amp;quot;a&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;an&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;the&amp;quot; that play an important syntactic role in English. They aren't just fillers that you can drop or insert anywhere! Most vernies are prone to dropping articles - &amp;quot;Houston, I have problem&amp;quot; they will say ... or there are the opposite kind who put in &amp;quot;Houston, I have the problem!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I can't come up with a coherent set of guidelines about articles right now ... might update this space later ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="myself"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Myself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one's not a result of bad grammar ... just a legacy of the British Raj ... the need to be as humble as possible when using the Gore Saheb's language, and over-doing it at that! People simply forget that the &amp;quot;myself&amp;quot; cannot be used as a subject, it has to be used as an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite often a person begins his own introduction as &amp;quot;Myself XYZ&amp;quot; as if that was a sentence in itself. &amp;quot;I am XYZ&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;My name is XYZ&amp;quot; is a complete sentence. &amp;quot;Myself XYZ&amp;quot; is just meaningless crap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIP: Remember that no English sentence in the active voice &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; begins with an object. And &amp;quot;myself&amp;quot; can only be used as an object. &amp;quot;Let me introduce myself. I am XYZ.&amp;quot; Or, if you are &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; kind of guy, remember the famous line &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0240772/"&gt;&amp;quot;My name is Zurga&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-your-kind-information"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For your (kind) information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another baddity (I wish that was a real word) that people seem to have picked up is the unnecessary use of &amp;quot;kind&amp;quot; in this phrase. It's simply incorrect! Doesn't compute!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to provide some information to someone, you can begin the sentence with &amp;quot;For your information, blah ...&amp;quot; putting a &amp;quot;kind&amp;quot; into that is simply wrong ... what could it possibly mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correct place for kind when responding to someone else's information by saying &amp;quot;Thanks for your &lt;em&gt;kind&lt;/em&gt; information!&amp;quot; That would be a slang contraction of &amp;quot;Thanks for being kind enough to provide this information!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIP: Remember the common chat acronym &amp;quot;FYI&amp;quot; ... it is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; &amp;quot;FYKI&amp;quot;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there's a subtle twist to this one ... &amp;quot;kind&amp;quot; is normally put in to denote a hint of sarcasm when the information provided was unwelcome ... &amp;quot;Thanks for your &lt;em&gt;kind&lt;/em&gt; information, but I never really asked for it, so shut up!&amp;quot; ... which is exactly what I am about to do, anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="idle thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>tea, and back again</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2004/08/04/tea-and-back-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-08-04T18:44:00+05:30</published><updated>2004-08-04T18:44:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2004-08-04:/2004/08/04/tea-and-back-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;How we spent the night of August 3rd, 2004&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;or&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;tea, and back again&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;or&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;a mid-monsoon night's adventure&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;by Chetan, Raghu, Sameer, Shantanu, Yug&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This is just the first draft. Further corrections expected, mostly involving timings and person-to-person accounts.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10pm generally loafing around in the dept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;11pm we go …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;How we spent the night of August 3rd, 2004&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;or&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;tea, and back again&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;or&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;a mid-monsoon night's adventure&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;by Chetan, Raghu, Sameer, Shantanu, Yug&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This is just the first draft. Further corrections expected, mostly involving timings and person-to-person accounts.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10pm generally loafing around in the dept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;11pm we go out for a birthday treat - guys only, so you can&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;imagine ;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1am we finish eating and drinking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:30 we decide to go out for a coffee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:35 we reach rhodas in hiranandani, for wonderful desserts coffee for 45 bucks is not worth it, so we decide to have that in hostel for only 7 bucks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2am we get out of rhodas and decide to have tea instead. at lonavla! (from here on, the timings are approximate, since no one looked at a watch) next couple of hours, we drive through tuffan rain, flooded roads, huge trucks on either side of us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4am we climb khandala, and run into an amazing fog ... standard place, where you go under a bridge for the old highway, and then enter a tunnel. so much fog, that we can only see the white strip in front of us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4:30 we travel through a deserted khandala, and equally deserted old highway to reach lonavla. don't forget torrential rain that you can barely see through, for the entire night and the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4:45 we finish tea at a really really small tapri by the road side, somewhere near lonavla station ... we don't really know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6am (this is an approximation, sometime around daybreak) we reach the spot just before khopoli exit, where the road from lonavla joins the expressway again. we stop the car for a bit of &amp;quot;relief&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6:10 the car starts, and there's a scraping noise. flat tyre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6:30 tyre changed, but now there's a thumping noise. the idea of getting out to khopoli for repairs was considered, but rejected. we drive slowly all the way to the toll both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:30 (the times may be completely off by now ... awaiting corrections from others) we wake up the mechanic, who actually refuses to wake up. After puncture repairs and further wheel repairs by another mechanic that refuses to wake up, the car's ready to go ... its one hour already!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8:30 back on the road. Again fighting huge trucks, potholes, rain and huge puddles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10am we reach IIT. breakfast at staff canteen. loads of misal, medhu vada, idli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11am finally, we accomplish what we set out for ... the 7-buck coffee at hostel 8! this is followed by a hot bath and a great sleep!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandatory declaration: Throughout the entire trip, all I did was sit in the back of the car, and sleep when appropriate. And yeah, I sang a couple of bad songs and made loads of excellent wisecracks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="outdoors"></category></entry><entry><title>Debian-ising IIT</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2004/02/20/debian-ising-iit/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-02-20T23:43:00+05:30</published><updated>2004-02-20T23:43:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2004-02-20:/2004/02/20/debian-ising-iit/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, so a lot of people in KReSIT have started using Debian. But havn't managed to get Prof. Arya to shift over to it yet! Where do we go from here? Liberating the whole institute from an infestation of Dead Rats, Salamanders, Magicians ... ;) Kinda sounds like the borg, doesn't it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, so a lot of people in KReSIT have started using Debian. But havn't managed to get Prof. Arya to shift over to it yet! Where do we go from here? Liberating the whole institute from an infestation of Dead Rats, Salamanders, Magicians ... ;) Kinda sounds like the borg, doesn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resistance is futile, you will be apt-getted!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;lt;/center&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Too bad the Debian ftp mirror on campus isn't maintained anymore ... so Debian fans are trying to put together their own caching-proxies. Best part is that the HoD of CSE, Prof. Siva has been assimilated now, and we can already see IBM PCs coming installed with Knoppix in CSE!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a short list of the major conspirators (former victims, maybe?):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~shourya/"&gt;Bhattacharya, Shouryapratap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~shantanu/"&gt;Godbole, Shantanu R.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cse.iitb.ac.in/vipul/"&gt;Mathur, Vipul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cse.iitb.ac.in/~yogi/"&gt;Patil, Preetam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/"&gt;Sahasrabuddhe, Sameer D.&lt;/a&gt; (me! me! In case you didn't notice ...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="free software"></category></entry><entry><title>hard disc trouble again ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2004/02/20/hard-disc-trouble-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-02-20T23:26:00+05:30</published><updated>2004-02-20T23:26:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2004-02-20:/2004/02/20/hard-disc-trouble-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;but Debian makes it sooooo painless!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 40GB hdd that I had shifted to, crashed some time ago ... and my trusty old 20GB is on the last legs of its &amp;quot;revolutionary&amp;quot; life. So, here we go again, moving house ... but with the automagical chroot install, you move everything - even the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;but Debian makes it sooooo painless!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 40GB hdd that I had shifted to, crashed some time ago ... and my trusty old 20GB is on the last legs of its &amp;quot;revolutionary&amp;quot; life. So, here we go again, moving house ... but with the automagical chroot install, you move everything - even the kitchen sink!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;But as always, there's a dark side to everything, and its invariably caused by the hordes of Mammon out there in Win-Win land! A modeling software I was using kinda loved the old hard-disc ... wouldn't run on the new one - &amp;quot;Invalid license,&amp;quot; it said, &amp;quot;incorrect disc ID!&amp;quot; So here I am, waiting for yet another license request to come through!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="computers"></category></entry><entry><title>Judge Dreaded</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/12/29/judge-dreaded/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-12-29T14:19:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-12-29T14:19:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-12-29:/2003/12/29/judge-dreaded/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Here's a quote from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.groklaw.net/"&gt;Groklaw&lt;/a&gt;, an excellent resource for those looking for a well-maintained and comprehensive guide to what's going on day-to-day surrounding the SCO controversy. The editor, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.groklaw.net/staticpages/index.php?page=20031004190519196"&gt;Pamela Jones&lt;/a&gt; remarks about her fascination for law while talking about a recent judgement in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20031220172203125"&gt;Verizon vs RIAA case&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The added …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Here's a quote from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.groklaw.net/"&gt;Groklaw&lt;/a&gt;, an excellent resource for those looking for a well-maintained and comprehensive guide to what's going on day-to-day surrounding the SCO controversy. The editor, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.groklaw.net/staticpages/index.php?page=20031004190519196"&gt;Pamela Jones&lt;/a&gt; remarks about her fascination for law while talking about a recent judgement in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20031220172203125"&gt;Verizon vs RIAA case&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The added &lt;em&gt;emphasis&lt;/em&gt; is mine ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This is what I love so much about the law. You hear nasty lawyer jokes all the time, I know. So do I. And when there are decisions in a court that people don't like, it's not unusual to hear some cracks about the judge and the legal system. But my view is that &lt;em&gt;these folks are what stand between us and chaos, between us and the bully process&lt;/em&gt;, whereby special interests grab whatever they want at the expense of everyone else, based on money and power. The parties naturally fight for what they perceive to be in their best interest. But judges are supposed to look at the bigger picture and to consider the impact on the general public as well. Frankly, &lt;em&gt;they sometimes seem to be the last ones in the scheme of things still reliably looking at anything but the bottom line&lt;/em&gt;. Decisions are sometimes disapointing, but now and then, a judge stands up and says: we have a rule of law here, and no matter who you are, no matter how much money you have, no matter how powerful your friends are, here in my courtroom, the law is applied fairly and without partiality. When you see it happen, it's a beautiful sight.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Judges don't do what they do for the money. They make an OK living, but there are easier ways to make money, lots more money than a judge will ever see, if he or she is honest. They do it because they love the law and the protections it is meant to provide to everyone, &lt;em&gt;they love finding the balance, the attempt to decide fairness&lt;/em&gt;, the interplay between private interests and Constitutional guarantees, the opportunity to &lt;em&gt;figure out what the framers of the Constitution and the lesser laws had in mind in the first place&lt;/em&gt;. The US legal system is based on the fundamental principle that when you go to court, it ought to actually be justice that you get. There has always been an idealism built into the country's judicial branch that moves my heart.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="life"></category><category term="hacked"></category></entry><entry><title>Mood-I ... from the trenches</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/12/25/mood-i-from-the-trenches/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-12-25T16:12:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-12-25T16:12:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-12-25:/2003/12/25/mood-i-from-the-trenches/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I decided to add a new section to my blog, where I want to talk about everyday people and events, that truly bring out the &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/blog.php?wl_mode=more&amp;amp;wl_eid=32&amp;amp;wl_topic=3"&gt;Carpe Diem&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; way of life. What better way to start the section, than by describing a posting from the internal newsgroups at IIT Bombay?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Here's …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I decided to add a new section to my blog, where I want to talk about everyday people and events, that truly bring out the &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/blog.php?wl_mode=more&amp;amp;wl_eid=32&amp;amp;wl_topic=3"&gt;Carpe Diem&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; way of life. What better way to start the section, than by describing a posting from the internal newsgroups at IIT Bombay?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Here's something that I overheard on iitb.general, by someone called Ashwin. I wonder if I'll ever meet him, or the other's nicknamed &amp;quot;Ghoda&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Machis&amp;quot;; but that's besides the point. For those (like me), who usually lag in the jargon-awareness department, &amp;quot;CG&amp;quot; is the title used for anyone on the &amp;quot;Core Group&amp;quot; that organises Mood Indigo, consisting of roughly 20-25 third-year BTech students.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Scene: Fusion nite, whole of OAT bursting to the brim, Shivamani on the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;drums. CGs are as busy as anything, but manage to grab a few minutes to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;watch the show. (I was just behind Ghoda and Machis at this time)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Shivamani asks for audience participation, and the response is huge,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;thousands clapping to the drum beats. Ghoda to Machis: &amp;quot;Great response&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;yaar!&amp;quot; And then the two just smiled at each other before moving on. And&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;the contentment on their faces said it all : the slog and sweat put&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;in paying off, it was a small moment which they will cherish forever,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;and whose simplicity and beauty I will never forget.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="life"></category><category term="hacked"></category></entry><entry><title>Carpe Diem!!!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/11/23/carpe-diem/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-23T17:43:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-11-23T17:43:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-11-23:/2003/11/23/carpe-diem/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;Sieze the day!&amp;quot; ... that's what it means ... &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Carpe Diem!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; and the phrase has captured my heart ever since I heard it. It points to the biggest problem that middle-class society faces, I believe - a lack of passion in what they believe.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I heard the phrase in a recent movie I …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;Sieze the day!&amp;quot; ... that's what it means ... &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Carpe Diem!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; and the phrase has captured my heart ever since I heard it. It points to the biggest problem that middle-class society faces, I believe - a lack of passion in what they believe.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I heard the phrase in a recent movie I saw, that immediately became one of my favourite movies - &lt;em&gt;The Dead Poets' Society&lt;/em&gt;. Its a story about a literature teacher John Keating (Robin Williams) from Welton High, a rigidly tradition-minded prep school for bright boys. Interestingly enough, there's a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.deliriumsrealm.com/delirium/movies/dps.asp"&gt;whole page&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to the philosophy of the movie, with a section on each character, including &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.deliriumsrealm.com/delirium/movies/dps_keating.asp"&gt;John Keating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He inspires his students to follow their passions, to think for themselves - &amp;quot;Carpe Diem, lads! Seize the day! Make your lives extraordinary!&amp;quot; - he says to his students in their first class. One of my favourite scenes is when he literally forces out a poem from the most introvert student in the class - Todd Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd was very shy. He couldn't speak to anyone of authority including answering questions in class without sounding insecure. However, by the end of the movie, Todd has found his voice and to show his loyalty to Keating, and that Keating actually taught him something valuable, he is the first to stand on his desk and call out to Keating as &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;O Captain! My Captain!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic reason for the problems people face is their lack of passion, I believe. &amp;quot;Ordinary man&amp;quot; is too engrossed in acquiring approval from peers and his elders harping on tradition - in fitting in with the flow - rather than following his heart and fulfilling his dreams. He is afraid to passionately work for something that he truly likes or truly believes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only he passionately followed his dreams and his instincts; if only he didn't cower under the wholly unnecessary fear of &amp;quot;public opinion&amp;quot; ... if instead he just went out and created a whole new path for himself ... the world would be a far more beautiful place than anyone can imagine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The media do seem to understand this. One of the hits from &lt;em&gt;Dil Chahta Hai&lt;/em&gt; goes &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Jab saaz hai, awaz hai, fir kisliye hichkichana! Gayenge hum, apne dilon ka tarana!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; I wonder how many fellow yuppies from my generation actually get the message. I wish everyone grew up with a John Keating to teach him!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="idle thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>Depression unlimited!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/11/11/depression-unlimited/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-11T00:01:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-11-11T00:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-11-11:/2003/11/11/depression-unlimited/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently earned a new name ... &amp;quot;Darwin&amp;quot;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People around here seem to have been bugged pretty bad by my generally depressed attitude. The last time I used my favourite remark, &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Man, this is not just pathetic, its downright depressing!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; dear old Shantanu got so bugged, he started looking for a new …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently earned a new name ... &amp;quot;Darwin&amp;quot;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People around here seem to have been bugged pretty bad by my generally depressed attitude. The last time I used my favourite remark, &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Man, this is not just pathetic, its downright depressing!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; dear old Shantanu got so bugged, he started looking for a new name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darwin, is a take-off on Marvin, the paranoid android, the perpetually depressed robot, from the Hitch Hikers' Guide, that goes &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Here I am, with a brain the size of a planet, and all they ask me to do is open doors!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Shut up&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;quot; Shantanu had said, &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;you think you are Marvin?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; ... and I had remarked rather passionately that Marvin was better off than I was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's how I ended up with my new name ... Darwin! SameerDS - that's me! Know my middle name? Its DARWIN ... even Marwin's afraid of me!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category><category term="marvin"></category></entry><entry><title>The two towers ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/11/01/the-two-towers/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-01T18:18:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-11-01T18:18:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-11-01:/2003/11/01/the-two-towers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This one's gonna be long. You have been warned! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I had been reflecting on life as a PG student, and what lies beyond ... what after I finish my doctorate? Who, or what, will I be? But before we get into that, let me describe the setting ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The third floor of …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This one's gonna be long. You have been warned! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I had been reflecting on life as a PG student, and what lies beyond ... what after I finish my doctorate? Who, or what, will I be? But before we get into that, let me describe the setting ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The third floor of KReSIT, where I sit, is just high enough, so that the surrounding tree-tops come at your eye-level. The floor has a balcony, where students generally hang out when taking small breaks. Above this sea of lush green, you see the Hirnandani complex to the left, and an unobstructed sunset to the right, from this balcony. I had never thought hard enough about the sight from the balcony, until it reminded me of &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings : The Two Towers&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; today.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ivory tower is an interesting place, I was thinking ... here, within our protected academic surroundings, we run a quaint little meritocratic system where people with smart brains rapidly gain importance. But what does all this importance actually accomplish in the long run, especially in the context of the entire world, that lies outside this tower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will I be when I have done my doctorate, and somehow managed to cruise past mid-age, when its time to look back and take stock of what I have accomplished? Do I want to be an &amp;quot;accomplished researcher&amp;quot; or is that just a fancy way of saying &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;anonymous engineer&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;? When I step out of academics, would anyone care about who I am or what I did? Would the guy next to me in the bus treat me with respect because I have a doctorate in engineering?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats when I noticed the Hiranandani complex, and the scene from LOTR came to my mind, with the transition from Saruman's toilings in Orthanc, to Sauron's all-seeing eye on Barad-dur. I was standing on a pretty building, that is part of an institute meant to be at the forefront of academic activities in India. And right across, stands one of the complexes in Mumbai that represent the rich - the ones with the real power and authority in todays world of the Vaishya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I really want to gain satisifaction in my life's work, I do have to make this choice some day - do I want to be the great researcher and anonymous engineer like the dwarves that made Sauron's rings, or do I want to go out in the world, learn its ways and hope to become Mithrandir one day?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="idle thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>Convocation snaps ... finally!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/10/30/convocation-snaps-finally/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-10-30T16:09:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-10-30T16:09:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-10-30:/2003/10/30/convocation-snaps-finally/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Better late, than never!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; they say ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Well, here they are - snaps from our &lt;a class="reference external" href="/~sameerds/snaps/convo/"&gt;Convocation&lt;/a&gt;, the day we became &amp;quot;praudyogiki nishnat&amp;quot; (Master of Technology). Just in case anyone wants to know &lt;em&gt;how late&lt;/em&gt;, the ceremony was conducted on Friday, 8th August, 2003.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Better late, than never!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; they say ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Well, here they are - snaps from our &lt;a class="reference external" href="/~sameerds/snaps/convo/"&gt;Convocation&lt;/a&gt;, the day we became &amp;quot;praudyogiki nishnat&amp;quot; (Master of Technology). Just in case anyone wants to know &lt;em&gt;how late&lt;/em&gt;, the ceremony was conducted on Friday, 8th August, 2003.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Discovering Pink Floyd</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/10/24/discovering-pink-floyd/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-10-24T00:27:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-10-24T00:27:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-10-24:/2003/10/24/discovering-pink-floyd/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a major &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~shantanu/bartending.html"&gt;night out&lt;/a&gt; in the hostel wing ... among other activities, one major accomplishment was getting to appreciate rock music in general, and Pink Floyd in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Tired of lying in the sunshine staying home to watch the rain
You are young and life is long and there …&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a major &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~shantanu/bartending.html"&gt;night out&lt;/a&gt; in the hostel wing ... among other activities, one major accomplishment was getting to appreciate rock music in general, and Pink Floyd in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Tired of lying in the sunshine staying home to watch the rain
You are young and life is long and there is time to kill today
And then one day you find that ten years have got behind you
No one told you when to run, you missed the starting gun&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Need I say more?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category></entry><entry><title>Arrival!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/10/18/arrival/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-10-18T22:59:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-10-18T22:59:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-10-18:/2003/10/18/arrival/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;PhD is a state of mind, not a degree,&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; they say! Well, one of the characteristics of this &amp;quot;state of mind&amp;quot; is the ability to make extra-ordinary statements about trivial matters, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The walk from hostel to department or back, is usually spent on such trivial matters of extreme …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;PhD is a state of mind, not a degree,&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; they say! Well, one of the characteristics of this &amp;quot;state of mind&amp;quot; is the ability to make extra-ordinary statements about trivial matters, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The walk from hostel to department or back, is usually spent on such trivial matters of extreme significance. Today was a rather productive day, since Shantanu and I came up with two great lines!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;First was when we saw a fellow student walk rapidly in what seemed like a great hurry to the department. We were walking at a rather slow pace, taking the sights along the way ... the best way to describe it?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;We never &lt;em&gt;go&lt;/em&gt; to a place, we &lt;em&gt;arrive&lt;/em&gt;!&amp;quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one was a result of a discussion about taking responsibility when things go wrong ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;If you want the &lt;em&gt;fame&lt;/em&gt;, gotta take the &lt;em&gt;blame&lt;/em&gt;. There's no &lt;em&gt;shame&lt;/em&gt; in that!&amp;quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category></entry><entry><title>a few treks ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/10/10/a-few-treks/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-10-10T11:11:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-10-10T11:11:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-10-10:/2003/10/10/a-few-treks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Been neglecting my brilliant idea of mainitaining a blog for quite some time now! Trekking in monsoon was great, hoping to continue with night-treks now!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Treks done so far - a sophies trek to Peb fort. It was great trek - good weather, enthu trekkers and great rains!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was after the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Been neglecting my brilliant idea of mainitaining a blog for quite some time now! Trekking in monsoon was great, hoping to continue with night-treks now!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Treks done so far - a sophies trek to Peb fort. It was great trek - good weather, enthu trekkers and great rains!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was after the trek to Nakhind - few people from KReSIT, a couple of alumni, and a couple of &amp;quot;outsiders&amp;quot;. The most remarkable part was being soaked in heavy rain for around 12 hours. Highly eventful trek, but too far back into the past, to write an account about!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, a dept trek! A busload of enthu punters went to Visapur - they had seen the snaps from the earlier trek to Visapur, but obviously this wasn't the same thing, since the rain gods were long gone. The climb down was especially great, since we abandoned the wide paved road and hit the cattle-track, searching for a fictitious &amp;quot;shortcut&amp;quot;. But the trek seems to have whetted people's appetite for outdoor activities - there's already demand for more!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="outdoors"></category></entry><entry><title>A section on Indic computing</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/09/27/a-section-on-indic-computing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-09-27T00:43:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-09-27T00:43:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-09-27:/2003/09/27/a-section-on-indic-computing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Recently started a new section on &lt;a class="reference external" href="/~sameerds/indic/"&gt;Indic Computing&lt;/a&gt;. It started as an intial post on a mailing list, explaining to people what &amp;quot;unicode&amp;quot; means and what's the difference between &amp;quot;fonts&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;encodings&amp;quot; ... there's not much on it currently, but I hope to start putting in some useful stuff and links …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Recently started a new section on &lt;a class="reference external" href="/~sameerds/indic/"&gt;Indic Computing&lt;/a&gt;. It started as an intial post on a mailing list, explaining to people what &amp;quot;unicode&amp;quot; means and what's the difference between &amp;quot;fonts&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;encodings&amp;quot; ... there's not much on it currently, but I hope to start putting in some useful stuff and links to relevant sites, especially those related to Indianization of the GNU. Hope to use PhpWiki and mod_rewrite to manage the &amp;quot;/indic/&amp;quot; section.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Kohli on developing India</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/09/04/kohli-on-developing-india/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-09-04T10:58:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-09-04T10:58:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-09-04:/2003/09/04/kohli-on-developing-india/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;F.C. Kohli had visited KReSIT yesterday, and delivered a free talk on where India stands today in IT age and how there's a lot to be done, with a bright future for the young generation. But two points that he made really stuck out in the entire session ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;About …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;F.C. Kohli had visited KReSIT yesterday, and delivered a free talk on where India stands today in IT age and how there's a lot to be done, with a bright future for the young generation. But two points that he made really stuck out in the entire session ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;About the general development efforts in the country, he remarked&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;All these are only attempts at optimising the sub-systems. Optimising subsystems has never resulted in a better overall system!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was also pretty passionate about introducing computers in the municipal schools, but pointed out the obvious that everyone has always managed to miss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes, I do want to introduce computers in schools, but not in order to make the children computer literate. The computers should be given to the teacher, to be used as a tool. The teacher should be trained to use the computer, in order to enhance the education being imparted to the children!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="life"></category><category term="hacked"></category></entry><entry><title>The "Linux" community ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/08/23/the-linux-community/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-08-23T12:12:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-08-23T12:12:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-08-23:/2003/08/23/the-linux-community/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Keeping politically correct nomenclature aside, here's a very nice comment on the community that powers free software and its cousins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
... The community that has gathered around Linux gathered not because it was a quick fix or an easy toy. They gathered because it was an intricate maze that offered constant …&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Keeping politically correct nomenclature aside, here's a very nice comment on the community that powers free software and its cousins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
... The community that has gathered around Linux gathered not because it was a quick fix or an easy toy. They gathered because it was an intricate maze that offered constant stimulation from a never ending supply of puzzles and thought experiments. More simply put, from the chaos of an infinitude of unsolved puzzles arose a well oiled machine that is capable of doing an extraordinary amount of good. ...&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Saw this on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.quantumlinux.com/"&gt;Quantum Linux Laboratories&lt;/a&gt; website, where they explain their daily &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.quantumlinux.com/cryptoquote/"&gt;cryptoquote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="free software"></category></entry><entry><title>The Debian chroot install</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/08/11/the-debian-chroot-install/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-08-11T12:11:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-08-11T12:11:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-08-11:/2003/08/11/the-debian-chroot-install/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The setting:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Existing Debian unstable installation on a 20GB hard-disk, and a new 40GB hard-disk with a small Windows partition.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The task:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Installing Debian on the new hard-disk and shifting over to it in the &amp;quot;near future&amp;quot;. But I want to do this without having to go through the painful …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The setting:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Existing Debian unstable installation on a 20GB hard-disk, and a new 40GB hard-disk with a small Windows partition.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The task:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Installing Debian on the new hard-disk and shifting over to it in the &amp;quot;near future&amp;quot;. But I want to do this without having to go through the painful bootable CD and stuff. Also, I have already partitioned the new hard-disk and formatted it with Reiserfs 3.6, which is unfortunately not supported by my old, kernel 2.2 based Debian boot CD.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The process:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;As Karsten M. Self at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twiki.iwethey.org/twiki/bin/view/Main/DebianChrootInstall"&gt;TwikiIWeThey&lt;/a&gt; says ...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
On the other hand, if you're experience with Debian, bored with convention, interested in a new challenge or feel that this method suits your current situation, read on. This method works in instances where a traditional Debian install doesn't, or would not be appropriate.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But actually I took his advice and decided to follow the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.debian.org/releases/stable/i386/ch-preparing.en.html#s-linux-upgrade"&gt;section&lt;/a&gt; on &amp;quot;zero-downtime&amp;quot; &amp;quot;cross-root&amp;quot; install in the Debian Installation Manual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Hard-disk partitions mounted under /mnt/debinst&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;apt-get&lt;/span&gt; install debootstrap&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;debootstrap&lt;/tt&gt; manual open in MozillaFirebird&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;em&gt;and so it begins ...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="computers"></category></entry><entry><title>Aliens ...</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/08/04/aliens/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-08-04T13:47:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-08-04T13:47:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-08-04:/2003/08/04/aliens/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;General conversation sitting on the KReSIT lawns turns towards aliens landing on planet Earth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If aliens land here, won't the laugh at us? Considering all those foolish depictions of aliens in Hollywood flicks&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Wonder if that's really true ... even they would have had similar concepts once upon a time ... &lt;em&gt;woh …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;General conversation sitting on the KReSIT lawns turns towards aliens landing on planet Earth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If aliens land here, won't the laugh at us? Considering all those foolish depictions of aliens in Hollywood flicks&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Wonder if that's really true ... even they would have had similar concepts once upon a time ... &lt;em&gt;woh kya aasman se thode hi tapke hain?&lt;/em&gt; Although, that is true in some sense!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Boss, aliens jab asman se tapkenge, &lt;em&gt;to kya khajoor me atkenge?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;;) And once again, have to mention &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~raghu/"&gt;Raghu&lt;/a&gt; for the last line!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category><category term="farts"></category></entry><entry><title>Moving hard disks - the saga continues</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/08/04/moving-hard-disks-the-saga-continues/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-08-04T11:03:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-08-04T11:03:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-08-04:/2003/08/04/moving-hard-disks-the-saga-continues/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Life would have been so easy if there was no need to install Windoze on the machine! But can't do without it, since &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.celoxica.com/"&gt;some software&lt;/a&gt; is available only on the Windoze platform.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Had started out with a Debian unstable installation with properly planned out partitions and all that. Along comes …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Life would have been so easy if there was no need to install Windoze on the machine! But can't do without it, since &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.celoxica.com/"&gt;some software&lt;/a&gt; is available only on the Windoze platform.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Had started out with a Debian unstable installation with properly planned out partitions and all that. Along comes the Windoze installer, decides that it owns my entire hard disk, and just goes ahead and formats &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;/dev/hda1&lt;/tt&gt; to be 40GB, simply ignoring the rest of the partition table!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I go again, repartitioning with the Windoze installer CD and making sure it understands it has only 4GB of the available face! Not to mention the fact that for some reason, my board gives up if I connect two hard-disks simultaneously. Wonder how I'll move my data ...&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="computers"></category></entry><entry><title>Moving to a larger hard disk</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/30/moving-to-a-larger-hard-disk/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-30T16:16:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-30T16:16:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-30:/2003/07/30/moving-to-a-larger-hard-disk/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;While the rest of the world goes into the terabyte age, I make a small move for myself ... shifting from a 20GB hard disk to a 40GB one. Tried out PGI aka &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hackers.progeny.com/pgi/"&gt;piggy&lt;/a&gt;, the cute little GUI installer for Debian. But it doesn't seem to have an option to use …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;While the rest of the world goes into the terabyte age, I make a small move for myself ... shifting from a 20GB hard disk to a 40GB one. Tried out PGI aka &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hackers.progeny.com/pgi/"&gt;piggy&lt;/a&gt;, the cute little GUI installer for Debian. But it doesn't seem to have an option to use Reiserfs, which is what I want to try out. So its back to one of the netinst CD images, the only problem is that the installer seems to have a 1024-cylinder limit, although LILO itself should not have a problem. So need to repartition, since I didn't consider that while making the initial partitions!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="computers"></category></entry><entry><title>Photos from the Visapur trek</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/30/photos-from-the-visapur-trek/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-30T15:29:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-30T15:29:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-30:/2003/07/30/photos-from-the-visapur-trek/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The photos from the Visapur trek are up! &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~abhijit/photos/"&gt;(here)&lt;/a&gt; These were taken from Abhijit's digital camera ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was one nice trek - very easy to climb, so easy in fact that we spent a lot of time just roaming along the way, and of course, having a great time in the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The photos from the Visapur trek are up! &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~abhijit/photos/"&gt;(here)&lt;/a&gt; These were taken from Abhijit's digital camera ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was one nice trek - very easy to climb, so easy in fact that we spent a lot of time just roaming along the way, and of course, having a great time in the streams! Visapur is a huge fort ... and so is Lohagad next to it. We walked a little more than three kilometers along the outer wall of the fort but still got to see only half of it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Nice pics of the car drive back to Mumbai, on the Express Highway are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~shantanu/pics/expressway.php"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="outdoors"></category></entry><entry><title>A trip to Pune and a "picnic" at Visapur</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/21/a-trip-to-pune-and-a-picnic-at-visapur/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-21T13:57:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-21T13:57:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-21:/2003/07/21/a-trip-to-pune-and-a-picnic-at-visapur/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Returned today from a general trip to Pune, that included a trek with the Veritas guys. Shantanu, Raghu, Ashish and I left for Pune on Friday evening in Raghu's car and returned today pre-lunch after a rather interesting stay for two days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of indecisive discussion, we went …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Returned today from a general trip to Pune, that included a trek with the Veritas guys. Shantanu, Raghu, Ashish and I left for Pune on Friday evening in Raghu's car and returned today pre-lunch after a rather interesting stay for two days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of indecisive discussion, we went off to Visapur for a trek on Saturday morning. What was supposed to be a rather nice trek, turned out to be more of a picnic, since Visapur is so damn easy to climb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Details coming up later when Abhijit, the MTech99 guy who now works in Veritas, manages to upload the photos. He has his own complaints about the Sysads (that includes me) about disk space, but that's a different story.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="outdoors"></category></entry><entry><title>Spaceship earth</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/17/spaceship-earth/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-17T10:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-17T10:34:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-17:/2003/07/17/spaceship-earth/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Overheard&amp;quot; this in an email &amp;quot;conversation&amp;quot; in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/"&gt;KReSIT&lt;/a&gt;, that I was dragged into, without consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I say bah to world peace! The sooner we screw up this planet the sooner we move out. Europa! here I come.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~raghu/"&gt;Raghu&lt;/a&gt; insists that I acknowledge him for that excellent(?) quote(??)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Overheard&amp;quot; this in an email &amp;quot;conversation&amp;quot; in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/"&gt;KReSIT&lt;/a&gt;, that I was dragged into, without consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I say bah to world peace! The sooner we screw up this planet the sooner we move out. Europa! here I come.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~raghu/"&gt;Raghu&lt;/a&gt; insists that I acknowledge him for that excellent(?) quote(??)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting to note what Smith says to Morpheus about humanity ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
You move to an area and you multiply and multiply until every natural resource is consumed and the only way you can survive is to spread to another area. There is another organism on this planet that follows the same pattern. Do you know what it is? A virus. Human beings are a disease, a cancer of this planet. You are a plague. And we are... the cure.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Judgement day is inevitable, said the T101 ... you did not prevent it, he said ... you merely &lt;em&gt;postponed&lt;/em&gt; it!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category><category term="farts"></category></entry><entry><title>Cheating on a pact</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/15/cheating-on-a-pact/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-15T17:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-15T17:36:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-15:/2003/07/15/cheating-on-a-pact/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Consider a situation where two guys make a pact, that they will &lt;em&gt;stop&lt;/em&gt; doing something that they normally &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; doing. Now depending how this pact came about to be, one can't really know which one of them, or both, is actually joking about the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So naturally, since they …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Consider a situation where two guys make a pact, that they will &lt;em&gt;stop&lt;/em&gt; doing something that they normally &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; doing. Now depending how this pact came about to be, one can't really know which one of them, or both, is actually joking about the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So naturally, since they normally &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; doing the thing that they agreed not to do, each will definitely enjoy &lt;em&gt;cheating&lt;/em&gt; on the other guy. But the enjoyment takes on a different nature when one of them gets discovered ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on the first guy, who was discovered, will have a guilt-complex about cheating anymore. Hey will continue cheating, since he can't resist it, but he won't really enjoy doing it. But the other guy will have a whale of a time - he gets to continue cheating, and in fact, his enjoyment is now enhanced by the other guy's guilt! All he has to do is be more careful about it, and continue harping on the fact that the first guy was discovered cheating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Samajhdaar ko ishara kaafi hai ;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="campus life"></category></entry><entry><title>A Wiki-based website in the pipes</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/15/a-wiki-based-website-in-the-pipes/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-15T00:22:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-15T00:22:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-15:/2003/07/15/a-wiki-based-website-in-the-pipes/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All that time spent in looking around for a content management system, surely left me with a great fascination for the Wiki way of managing information. Simply using your browser to create new pages with no need to worry about files is too good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;So here goes - a very shameless …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;All that time spent in looking around for a content management system, surely left me with a great fascination for the Wiki way of managing information. Simply using your browser to create new pages with no need to worry about files is too good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;So here goes - a very shameless hack at PHPWiki to use it as a CMS for a single website! But I am already happy with the results; it would be so easy to maintain that version of the website! `
Check it out! &amp;lt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/phpwiki/index.php"&gt;http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/phpwiki/index.php&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;`__&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Two things worth mentioning here - PHPWiki has this excellent plugin architecture that allows you to extend the features in arbitrary manners. I already used that to create a plugin for &amp;quot;RichTables&amp;quot; ... the native support is simply not good enough if you care about the layout of your personal webpage. My plugin allows me to specify table and cell properties individually - I wonder if any Wiki implementation does that very well.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next plugin planned is to have an interface between the blog and the Wiki-powered site. That would allow me to include data generated from the blog into any part of the Wiki. Not possible right now, but yeah its doable! Don't think I'll be using the Wiki version until I get this plugin in place!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Debianising KReSIT</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/14/debianising-kresit/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-14T20:50:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-14T20:50:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-14:/2003/07/14/debianising-kresit/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, Debian begins to get counted among the &amp;quot;respectable&amp;quot; Distros used in KReSIT. The DEP intends to use customised Knoppix CD's for the Foundations Lab course, while more and more people opt to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.debian.org/"&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt; on their machines. Best part was getting Prof. Arya to agree to use …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, Debian begins to get counted among the &amp;quot;respectable&amp;quot; Distros used in KReSIT. The DEP intends to use customised Knoppix CD's for the Foundations Lab course, while more and more people opt to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.debian.org/"&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt; on their machines. Best part was getting Prof. Arya to agree to use Debian ... the selling point? He gets guaranteed support from &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full credits to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.knoppix.net/"&gt;Knoppix&lt;/a&gt; CD's which make it so easy to impress newbies into making The Right Choice (tm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Too bad Debian stable tends to get out of date very easily, or I wouldn't have spared the KReSIT servers either. Debian unstable would have been good enough, but the &amp;quot;unstable&amp;quot; in the name tends to scare people away.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="free software"></category></entry><entry><title>First hack at Weblog</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/14/first-hack-at-weblog/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-14T04:25:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-14T04:25:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-14:/2003/07/14/first-hack-at-weblog/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Two hours into stability, and here's the first hack ... a php script that posts the latest five blog entries in a rather disciplined manner.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Another example of too much free time on hand?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Two hours into stability, and here's the first hack ... a php script that posts the latest five blog entries in a rather disciplined manner.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Another example of too much free time on hand?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>A website with a blog!</title><link href="https://pelican.sbuddhe.net/2003/07/14/a-website-with-a-blog/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-07-14T03:04:00+05:30</published><updated>2003-07-14T03:04:00+05:30</updated><author><name>sameer</name></author><id>tag:pelican.sbuddhe.net,2003-07-14:/2003/07/14/a-website-with-a-blog/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally ... a blog for my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/old_index.html"&gt;hitherto inert&lt;/a&gt; website!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days of exploraion in the world of Wiki setups and content management systems, and I settle on &amp;quot;Personal Weblog&amp;quot; ... the extremely simple, matter-of-fact util for a hassle-free blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting how one easily drifts into the feature-bloat quagmire when goes shopping in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally ... a blog for my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.iitb.ac.in/~sameerds/old_index.html"&gt;hitherto inert&lt;/a&gt; website!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days of exploraion in the world of Wiki setups and content management systems, and I settle on &amp;quot;Personal Weblog&amp;quot; ... the extremely simple, matter-of-fact util for a hassle-free blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting how one easily drifts into the feature-bloat quagmire when goes shopping in the Open Source World. I started out looking for a way to help post comments on my &amp;quot;planned&amp;quot; jewel of a website. Finally did find something useful after two days (and one sleepless night!) of unnecessary searching, because it was oh-so-tempting to have a personal Wiki-style interface to edit my own website!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;But anyway, here it is now ... a plain html webpage with a simple little blogger.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="meta"></category></entry></feed>